<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://grovetech.co/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://grovetech.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2021-11-14T22:24:21-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/atom.xml</id><title type="html"> - Mac Support DC</title><subtitle>Grove Technologies - Washington DC's best Mac Support company for Digital Agencies, Creative Professionals &amp; Non Profits.</subtitle><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><entry><title type="html">Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try" /><published>2021-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Need-to-Resize-Images-in-Various-Ways-Give-Preview-a-Try.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try&quot;&gt;Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even those of us who don’t work with graphics professionally often find
ourselves needing to resize images. Perhaps you have a large square
headshot, but the site to which you’re uploading requires it to be
exactly 100 by 100 pixels. Or maybe you have an iPhone 13 Pro photo
that’s 4032 by 3024, but you need the long side to be 1280 pixels and
the short side to be 800 pixels. You might even need to cut out an
800-by-600 rectangle from a much larger image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tasks are easily accomplished with professional graphics apps like
Photoshop, but you don’t need to pay for or learn Photoshop for a quick
resizing and cropping of an image. That’s because Preview, which is
built into macOS, can do many of these tasks with aplomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One note: You can resize images to be smaller with little or no loss of
quality, but you can’t make images bigger without them looking fuzzier
unless you employ specialized tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shrink-an-image-without-changing-aspect-ratio&quot;&gt;Shrink an Image without Changing Aspect Ratio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take our first example above. We have a square headshot that we
need to upload to an account, but the site won’t accept an image larger
than 100 pixels square. To shrink the image to the specified size, we’ll
first make a copy in the Finder or we’ll open the file in Preview and
choose File &amp;gt; Duplicate. Then, with the image open in Preview, we’ll
choose Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size, make sure “pixels” is chosen to the right
of the Width and Height fields, and enter 100 into the Width field.
Because Scale Proportionally is selected, Height automatically changes
to 100 to match. We’ll click OK to exit the dialog and then save the
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shrink-an-image-and-crop-to-different-dimensions&quot;&gt;Shrink an Image and Crop to Different Dimensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s move on to our second example above. We have a photo of some
home-baked bread loaves that we’ve taken with the iPhone, and we need to
resize it to 1280 by 800 pixels before uploading it to our food blog.
There are two problems: the image is much larger than we need to start,
and when we try resizing it to the desired pixel count in one dimension,
the other dimension is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start the same way we did before, by making a copy of the original
and in Preview choosing Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size. In the Image Dimensions
dialog, we’ll first type 1280 into the Width field. In this example,
doing that causes the Height field to change to 752, which is too small
(below left). Remember, shrinking images is easy and works well, but
expanding them is hard. So instead, we’ll type 800 into the Height
field, which causes the Width field to change to 1361 (below right).
That’s good; we’ll click OK to resize the image. It will look small, but
we can zoom it back to the window size by choosing View &amp;gt; Zoom to Fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image3.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next step, we need to get the image width down from 1361 to 1280
pixels, which we do by cropping. Choose Edit &amp;gt; Select All (or just
press Command-A), and notice that there’s a selection rectangle around
the entire image, with blue drag handles in the middle of each side and
at each corner. We’ll need to take some off each side to keep the loaves
centered, so we’ll drag the left side in a little to start. If you have
trouble grabbing the blue drag handles instead of the edge of Preview’s
window, choose View &amp;gt; Zoom Out to zoom out one step and separate the
handles from the window edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we’ll drag the right side in. Notice that as we drag, Preview
displays the image dimensions in a little lozenge (at the right in the
screenshot)—we’ve stopped at 1280. Since we’re moving only the edges,
only the width changes—resizing from the corners would be much harder
because both dimensions would change simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tip. If you’ve gotten the selection rectangle to 1280 by 800, but
the content under it isn’t centered as you’d like, press and hold the
left or right arrow key to move the selection rectangle to the left or
right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have the selection rectangle at the right size and in the right
place, we’ll choose Tools &amp;gt; Crop to discard the image content outside
the selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extract-a-portion-of-an-image-with-specific-dimensions&quot;&gt;Extract a Portion of an Image with Specific Dimensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our final example, let’s assume that we have a large picture of
cherry tomatoes, and we need to cut out just the black tomatoes for a
Web page that requires an 800-by-600 image. Once again, the image is too
large, but the trickier problem is that we only need a small portion of
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by dragging out a selection rectangle that’s roughly 800 by
600, using Preview’s measurement lozenge. All we’re doing here is
getting a sense of what the shape of 800 by 600 looks like. Then we make
another selection around the black cherry tomatoes that’s roughly the
same aspect ratio, wider than it is tall. The details don’t matter much
at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to crop the photo to the selection with Tools &amp;gt; Crop.
Then we choose Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size and set the Width field to 800 to
get the width correct. That reveals that the height of our rough crop
was slightly too large, at 630 pixels. We’ll click OK to resize the
image to those dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll use the same technique we did in the example above, with
Select All, dragging the top handle down until the dimensions are 800 by
600, and then using Tools &amp;gt; Crop to discard the extra content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can do a lot with just three basic techniques in
Preview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size to resize the entire image&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dragging out selection rectangles while paying attention to the
measurements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Tools &amp;gt; Crop to get rid of content outside the selection
rectangle&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won’t pretend that Preview is the ultimate graphics tool, but it’s
capable, easy to use, and on every Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More" /><published>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Use-Visual-Look-Up-in-Photos-in-iOS-15-to-Identify-Plants,-Pets,-and-More.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants-pets-and-more&quot;&gt;Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to identify a plant, flower, or pet breed, or find
out what that famous painting is called? Us too. In iOS 15 and iPadOS
15, Apple added a new AI-driven feature called Visual Look Up that
provides more information about photos of plants, flowers, pets, books,
artworks, and landmarks. When you’re viewing a photo, swipe up or tap
the sparkle-badged info button ➊ to see metadata about the image (camera
model, image details, location, and more) and then tap Look Up to learn
more ➋. Depending on the item recognized, it will suggest Wikipedia
articles, similar images from the Web, websites, bookstores, map
locations, and more. Tap a suggestion to switch to Safari or another app
for details. (If the info button doesn’t have the sparkle badge, Visual
Look Up hasn’t identified anything in the photo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Us/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021" /><published>2021-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/The-Best-Apple-Related-Gifts-for-2021.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021&quot;&gt;The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem early to start thinking about the holiday shopping season,
but with the global supply chain suffering pandemic-related slowdowns,
there’s no telling how long it will take to get something you order
today. Apple has generally done a good job of managing its supply chain
issues, but even still, if you want to make sure you have an Apple
something for that special someone, we recommend buying it soon. Here
are our recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airtag&quot;&gt;AirTag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know someone who’s always misplacing their keys, purse, or
backpack? Apple’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airtag/&quot;&gt;AirTag&lt;/a&gt;
tracker is the perfect gift for such a person. Attach one to a keyring
(with a separate $29 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYY3ZM/A/airtag-loop-pink-citrus&quot;&gt;AirTag
Loop&lt;/a&gt;
or $39 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM043ZM/A/airtag-leather-loop-baltic-blue&quot;&gt;AirTag Leather
Loop&lt;/a&gt;)
or drop it in a bag, and from then on, the person can use the Find My
app to see where they left their stuff. Support for ultra-wideband
enables precision finding with an iPhone 11 or later—with earlier
iPhones, the detected location won’t be quite so precise. AirTag uses
the Find My network, so even if the item is far away, passing Apple
devices that detect it can securely share its location with you. One
AirTag costs $29, or you can get a pack of four for $99. You can even
have Apple personalize each AirTag with custom text and emoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airpods-and-airpods-pro&quot;&gt;AirPods and AirPods Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s wireless earbuds remain popular, and the company just released
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-3rd-generation/&quot;&gt;third-generation
AirPods&lt;/a&gt; to
supplement the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-2nd-generation/&quot;&gt;second-generation
AirPods&lt;/a&gt; and the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-pro/&quot;&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;. All three make
excellent gifts. The second-generation AirPods cost $129, have a
relatively long stalk, and boast up to 5 hours of listening on one
charge. The $179 third-generation AirPods shrink the stalk, switch to a
force sensor for controls, add support for spatial audio with dynamic
head tracking, feature sweat and water resistance, have a MagSafe
wireless charging case, and last up to 6 hours on a single charge. For
$249, the AirPods Pro include the features of the third-generation
AirPods and add silicone ear tips and active noise cancellation with
optional transparency mode, but they have only 4.5 hours of listening
time. All three have charging cases, support Hey Siri commands, and
automatically switch between Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homepod-mini&quot;&gt;HomePod mini&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Apple discontinued the full-size HomePod, which
wasn’t a big hit at its relatively high price of $299. However, the
$99 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/homepod-mini/&quot;&gt;HomePod mini&lt;/a&gt; remains
available, and Apple is now selling it in five colors, with blue,
orange, and yellow joining white and black. (The new colors will become
available at some point in November.) The grapefruit-sized HomePod mini
may be small, but it produces great sound for its size, and it can do
pretty much everything the larger HomePod could do. You can control it
entirely via Siri, pair two for stereo sound, use it as a hub for your
HomeKit home automation accessories, and even have it play the sound
from your Apple TV. Put a HomePod mini in different rooms in the house,
and you can use Intercom to communicate with family members using your
voice. If you’re giving it as a gift, remember that it’s best when
paired with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-music/&quot;&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;
subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ipad-and-ipad-mini&quot;&gt;iPad and iPad mini&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to give an iPad as a gift, you have a lot of choice.
The top-of-the-line &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-pro/&quot;&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;
may be overkill for most given its power and price—$799 for the
11-inch model and $1099 for the 12.9-inch model. But the
fourth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-air/&quot;&gt;iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;,
which starts at $599, provides sufficient power for even the most
intensive tasks, especially when coupled with a second-generation
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-pencil/&quot;&gt;Apple Pencil&lt;/a&gt; ($129) and
either a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;
($299) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Smart Keyboard
Folio&lt;/a&gt; ($179).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those possibilities seem pricey for an iPad that’s destined for a kid
or an adult with basic needs, look no further than the new
ninth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-10.2/&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, which
remains a bargain at $329. It works with the first-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-pencil/&quot;&gt;Apple
Pencil&lt;/a&gt; ($99), and those who
need to write can add the $159 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Smart
Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, don’t
forget the sixth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-mini/&quot;&gt;iPad
mini&lt;/a&gt;, which benefited from a
major redesign back in September. It’s now more like a diminutive
version of the iPad Air, with more colors and a squared-off industrial
design compatible with the second-generation Apple Pencil. It’s $499,
and if you need a keyboard, you’ll have to look to a third-party
manufacturer or use a standard Bluetooth wireless keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apple-watch-gift-certificate&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Gift Certificate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but far from least, we love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/watch/&quot;&gt;Apple
Watch&lt;/a&gt;, and it would seem to make a
great gift. However, we urge caution. Apple provides a dizzying number
of options for case size, material, and color, plus the band and color,
making it difficult to know what would be most appreciated. So we’d
encourage giving a certificate that’s good for a conversation about what
to purchase. Then sit down with the recipient to run through all the
decisions in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/studio&quot;&gt;Apple Watch
Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three options this year: the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-6/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Series
7&lt;/a&gt; (starting at
$399), last year’s less expensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-se/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch
SE&lt;/a&gt; (starting at $279), or
the much older &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-3/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Series
3&lt;/a&gt; (starting at
$199). Get the Series 7 if you want an Always-On Display, blood oxygen
sensor, and ECG capabilities—it also boasts a larger screen than last
year’s Series 6 while remaining compatible with all the bands. The Apple
Watch SE lacks the Series 7’s advanced sensors and has a slightly
smaller screen size, but it still provides the compass, altimeter, and
fall detection features. The screen on the Series 3 is smaller yet, and
it lacks a number of key features. Unless keeping the cost to a minimum
is essential, we have a hard time recommending the Series 3—it’s
getting too old. Apple has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/watch/compare/&quot;&gt;helpful comparison
tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that we didn’t include any Macs in this article.
They are worthy gifts, but they’re quite a bit more expensive and more
difficult to select without extensive discussion of the recipient’s
needs. Let us know if you need help choosing the right Mac for someone
on your list, but we’re partial to the M1-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/macbook-air/&quot;&gt;MacBook
Air&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/imac-24/&quot;&gt;24-inch
iMac&lt;/a&gt; for many users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing" /><published>2021-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/With-Apple-Watch-Faces,-Too-Much-Choice-Can-Be-Confusing.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;with-apple-watch-faces-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing&quot;&gt;With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch has a lot to offer older people, including heart rate
monitoring, atrial fibrillation detection, fall detection, and
electrocardiogram recording. But if you are—or are helping someone who
is—of the generation where watches once did nothing beyond telling the
time, too many options can be overwhelming. Adding to the confusion is
how easy it is to create and accidentally swipe between multiple watch
faces, making it so the Apple Watch suddenly looks and works completely
differently. If that’s an issue, use the Watch app to delete all but the
preferred watch face. In Watch &amp;gt; My Watch, tap Edit to the right of My
Faces ➊, tap the red delete button next to a face ➋, and then tap Remove
➌.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Wi/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iPadOS Multitasking</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPadOS Multitasking" /><published>2021-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/iPadOS-Multitasking.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-radically-improved-multitasking-in-ipados-15-heres-how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Apple Radically Improved Multitasking in iPadOS 15. Here’s How to Use It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multitasking has long been a mess on the iPad, not so much because it
didn’t work but because it was tough to memorize the secret swipes
necessary to put multiple apps into Split View, work with multiple
windows in apps that supported them, and hide and show what you wanted
in Slide Over. In iPadOS 15, Apple hasn’t changed the underlying
multitasking capabilities much, but it has made them far more
discoverable with onscreen controls and tips that supplement the
previous gestures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-multitasking-menu&quot;&gt;Use the Multitasking Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most important is the new multitasking menu button that appears in the
top center of every app, represented by •••. Tap it to reveal a control
with three options—Full Screen, Split View, and Slide Over—and then
tap one of those to put the current app into that mode. From left:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Screen:&lt;/strong&gt; When only a single app is showing, the leftmost
button is selected. When you have an app in Split View or Slide
Over, tap the Full Screen button to make that app the only one
onscreen.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Split View:&lt;/strong&gt; Tap the middle button to shove the current app to
the left edge of the screen, revealing the Home screen and the Dock.
A little lozenge replaces the multitasking menu, telling you that
you’re working with Split View and to choose another app. Tap any
other app to open it (on the right side) with the current app (on
the left side), and remember that you can resize each app using the
handle on the black bar in the middle.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide Over:&lt;/strong&gt; In the current app window, tap the rightmost button
to push the app to the side of the screen, again revealing the Home
screen and the Dock and showing a lozenge that tells you that you’re
working with Slide Over and to choose another app. Tap any other to
open it full screen but with the current app floating above it in
Slide Over mode, and remember that you can hide the Slide Over app
easily by swiping it to the right.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-app-switcher&quot;&gt;Use the App Switcher&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple also made it much easier to see and manage your Split View
combinations by using the App Switcher. Once you go into it by swiping
up from the bottom of the screen (or double-pressing the Home button, if
your iPad has one), you have several multitasking-related options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch among apps:&lt;/strong&gt; Tap any app, Split View combination, or Slide
Over app (located on the right side of the App Switcher) to switch
to it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a Split View:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag any app or window onto another one to
combine them into a Split View (as is shown with Drive and Docs
below). Before you start to drag, pause for a moment to pick up the
app; drag until the items turn into icon-emblazoned gray rectangles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replace a Split View app:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag any app or window onto the left
or right side of a Split View combination to replace that app or
window.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Break a Split View combination:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag the left or right side of a
Split View combination off until it displays as a full-screen
thumbnail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the screenshot above, note the red arrow pointing to the little
stacked square icons above the Safari Split View windows. Those indicate
that the app in question has multiple windows. Tap the icon to display
just that app’s windows in the App Switcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-shelf&quot;&gt;Use the Shelf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The App Switcher may make it easier to see and switch among multiple
windows in apps, but another new multitasking feature, the Shelf, is
even more useful. When you use the Dock or a search to open an app with
multiple windows available, the Shelf displays them all at the bottom of
the screen. The Shelf doesn’t appear when you switch to an app using the
App Switcher or four-finger swipe, but you can bring it up at any time
by tapping the multitasking menu button at the top of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re looking at items on the Shelf, tap one to switch to it. You
can also swipe up on windows on the Shelf to close them. As soon as you
tap anywhere else in the app to start working, the Shelf disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-center-windows&quot;&gt;Use Center Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In at least some apps with sidebars, such as Mail and Notes, you can now
open an item like a message or a note in its own window in the center of
the screen. That’s useful for previewing the full content of the item,
and you can swipe down on the multitasking menu button to put the window
on the Shelf, which keeps it available for quick reference while you
work on something else. To create a center window, touch and hold the
item in the sidebar and then tap Open in New Window. To close it, tap
Close or swipe up on its Shelf thumbnail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image8.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-multitasking-keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Use the Multitasking Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seriously interested in using multitasking on an iPad, you’re
probably also working with a physical keyboard much of the time. In
iPadOS 15, Apple added a useful set of keyboard shortcuts that you can
learn about by pressing and holding the Globe key and then tapping the
Multitasking tab at the bottom. It may take a little while to
internalize the shortcuts, but if you do most of your work on an iPad,
you will probably find the effort worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image9.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like the idea of multitasking on the iPad but have never been
able to remember all the necessary gestures, iPadOS 15’s changes will be
welcome. Give them a try—we think they finally make multitasking
obvious enough for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Apple Radically Improved Multitasking in iPadOS 15. Here’s How to Use It</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iPhone 13 Upgrade Quick Start</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPhone 13 Upgrade Quick Start" /><published>2021-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/iPhone-upgrade-Quick-Start.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-migrating-to-a-new-iphone-or-ipad-try-quick-start-first&quot;&gt;When Migrating to a New iPhone or iPad, Try Quick Start First&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a new iPhone or iPad—congratulations! When transferring your
data to the new device, you have three options: &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210216&quot;&gt;Quick
Start&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204184&quot;&gt;iCloud
backup&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204184&quot;&gt;Mac
backup&lt;/a&gt;. All will work,
but they don’t quite provide the same end result (particularly if you
didn’t encrypt your Mac backup). Our advice—backed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2021/09/24/how-to-set-up-a-new-iphone-or-ipad&quot;&gt;this post from
Apple expert John
Gruber&lt;/a&gt;—is
to try Quick Start first because it transfers everything directly from
your old device to your new one, maintaining app logins in most cases
and allowing you to transfer your Apple Watch pairing. It may seem like
it’s taking a long time before you can use the device, but it’s worth it
to avoid logging in to numerous apps and unpairing and repairing your
Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">When Migrating to a New iPhone or iPad, Try Quick Start First</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iMessages not delivered</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/imessages-not-delivered/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iMessages not delivered" /><published>2021-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/iMessages-not-delivered.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/imessages-not-delivered/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;messages-not-being-delivered-to-blue-bubble-friends-check-cellular-data&quot;&gt;Messages Not Being Delivered to Blue-Bubble Friends? Check Cellular Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a tricky situation that threw one of our clients for a loop
recently. Texts they sent in Messages via iMessage (indicated by blue
bubbles) to their son, letting him know they were stopping by weren’t
being delivered, making their visits a surprise. But other texts worked
fine. The problem, it turned out, was that Cellular Data had somehow
gotten turned off in Settings &amp;gt; Cellular. So messages worked fine as
long as the iPhone was on Wi-Fi at home, but as soon as they were on the
road using a cellular connection, the iPhone could no longer communicate
with the Internet. In theory, Messages should fall back to SMS
(indicated by green bubbles), which doesn’t require cellular data, but
that doesn’t always happen. The fix? Just enable Settings &amp;gt; Cellular &amp;gt;
Cellular Data again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iM/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Messages Not Being Delivered to Blue-Bubble Friends? Check Cellular Data</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SMS.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SMS.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New M1 Pro and M1 Max Chips Power the 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/new-macbooks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New M1 Pro and M1 Max Chips Power the 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros" /><published>2021-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/New-MacBooks.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/new-macbooks/">&lt;p&gt;Last year, Apple started to transition Macs away from Intel processors
to its custom M1 system-on-a-chip. The M1’s performance is stellar, but
Apple has used it only in low-end models so far: the MacBook Air,
13-inch MacBook Pro, Mac mini, and new 24-inch iMac. For professionals
looking for more power, Apple unveiled the future of high-end Macs at
its October 18th
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2021/&quot;&gt;Unleashed&lt;/a&gt;
event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two new chips—the M1 Pro and M1 Max—increase performance
significantly beyond the M1, and Apple built them into new 14-inch and
16-inch MacBook Pro models along with features that respond to
criticisms of previous models. Welcome as these new MacBook Pros are,
many people were also hoping to see an Apple silicon refresh of the
popular 27-inch iMac. That didn’t happen, but Apple released several
other music-related products and services at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airpods-homepod-mini-apple-music-and-monterey-announcements&quot;&gt;AirPods, HomePod mini, Apple Music, and Monterey Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a quick set of announcements at the start of its event, Apple
revealed an update to the popular AirPods, new colors of the HomePod
mini, and a budget pricing tier for Apple Music. Plus, press releases
revealed the ship date for macOS 12 Monterey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-generation AirPods:&lt;/strong&gt; Building on the success of the classic
AirPods and AirPods Pro, Apple redesigned the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-3rd-generation/&quot;&gt;third-generation
AirPods&lt;/a&gt; to
have shorter mic stalks, force sensor controls, support for spatial
audio, Adaptive EQ, longer battery life, wireless case charging, and
sweat and water resistance. They cost $179; the second-generation
AirPods remain available for $129.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New HomePod mini colors:&lt;/strong&gt; Looking to coordinate your electronics
with your decor? In November, the $99 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/homepod-mini/&quot;&gt;HomePod
mini&lt;/a&gt; will be available
in blue, orange, and yellow, as well as the traditional black and
white.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Music Voice Plan:&lt;/strong&gt; A new $4.99-per-month &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-music/&quot;&gt;Apple Music
Voice Plan&lt;/a&gt; reduces the
cost of Apple Music for those who interact with the streaming
service largely through Siri, but it lacks lyrics, music videos,
spatial and lossless audio, and support for non-Apple devices.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS 12 Monterey release date:&lt;/strong&gt; Hidden in the fine print in
Apple’s press releases was the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/macos/monterey/&quot;&gt;macOS 12
Monterey&lt;/a&gt;—along with
iOS 15.1, iPadOS 15.1, watchOS 8.1, and tvOS 15.1—will become
available on October 25th. We strongly recommend that you do not
upgrade to Monterey until we give the go-ahead. If you’ve already
upgraded to the other new operating systems, it should be safe to
install those updates a week or two after release.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-14-inch-and-16-inch-macbook-pros-answer-customer-desires&quot;&gt;New 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros Answer Customer Desires&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s professional &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/macbook-pro/&quot;&gt;MacBook
Pro&lt;/a&gt; has been a workhorse of
the Mac lineup for years, offering high-end performance in a portable
package. Since 2016, however, customers have expressed irritation at
Apple’s removal of ports other than Thunderbolt 3, the loss of MagSafe
magnetic charging, and the Touch Bar replacing traditional F-keys.
Here’s how the new MacBook Pros respond to those concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ports:&lt;/strong&gt; Previously, the MacBook Pro had just four Thunderbolt 3
ports, forcing users to carry dongles to connect to legacy devices.
The new models still lack USB-A ports but supplement three
Thunderbolt 4 ports with an HDMI port for video, an SDXC card slot
for camera media, and a headphone jack.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MagSafe:&lt;/strong&gt; Although you can charge using the Thunderbolt 4 ports,
most people will rely on the dedicated MagSafe 3 charging port. The
MacBook Pros (apart from the low-end 14-inch model) include powerful
chargers and a USB-C to MagSafe 3 charging cable capable of
fast-charging the devices. They should also provide longer battery
life than previous models.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F-keys with Touch ID:&lt;/strong&gt; The Touch Bar hasn’t been a success, never
migrating to any other Mac models and eliciting tepid support from
developers. With these new MacBook Pros, Apple has reversed course,
replacing the Touch Bar with traditional F-keys. A Touch ID sensor
remains available for authentication at the top-right corner of the
keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Apple did equip the 13-inch MacBook Pro with an M1 chip in
November 2020, it wasn’t notably faster than the cheaper but largely
comparable M1-based MacBook Air. We suspect no one will be complaining
about the performance of the new 14-inch and 16-inch models thanks to
the addition of Apple’s just-released M1 Pro and M1 Max chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M1:&lt;/strong&gt; For reference, last year’s M1 chip—widely acclaimed for
providing excellent performance—offers an 8-core CPU with four
performance and four efficiency cores, a 7-core or 8-core GPU, and
either 8 GB or 16 GB of unified memory.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M1 Pro:&lt;/strong&gt; The M1 Pro offers up to 1.7 times the performance of the
M1 thanks to a 10-core CPU that has eight performance and two
efficiency cores. Plus, its 16-core GPU is up to twice as fast as
the M1. The M1 Pro provides either 16 GB or 32 GB of unified memory,
and it increases the memory bandwidth by nearly three times, up to
200 gigabytes per second (GBps). To provide lower price points for
14-inch MacBook Pro configurations, Apple offers versions of the M1
Pro with an 8-core CPU (six performance and two efficiency cores) or
a 14-core GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M1 Max:&lt;/strong&gt; The M1 Max has the same 10-core CPU as the M1 Pro but
provides a massive 32-core GPU with up to four times the performance
of the M1. The largest chip Apple has ever made, the M1 Max offers
either 32 GB or 64 GB of memory, and it doubles the M1 Pro’s memory
bandwidth to 400 GBps, nearly six times faster than the M1. A
lower-cost M1 Max configuration has a 24-core GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the M1 Pro and M1 Max feature an Apple-designed media engine that
accelerates video processing while maximizing battery life. Both also
have dedicated acceleration for the ProRes professional video codec for
working with 4K and 8K video. The M1 Max doubles the M1 Pro’s
performance for video encoding and provides two ProRes accelerators. In
other words, if you’re working with video, these new Macs are going to
scream, particularly with an M1 Max.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple didn’t stop after radically improving performance and bringing
back beloved features. The new MacBook Pros feature new Liquid Retina
XDR displays based on technology used in the latest iPad Pro models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most notably, for those who need more screen space than the 13-inch
MacBook Pro can provide, the new MacBook Pro models have higher
resolution displays. The 14-inch screen has a 3024-by-1964 native
resolution that’s slightly larger than the previous 16-inch MacBook Pro
(3072‑by‑1920), and the new 16-inch model offers even more pixels with a
3456-by-2234 resolution. The new displays are more than twice as bright
as the previous models, and they support ProMotion, which adjusts the
screen refresh rate (and thus power consumption) to match the needs of
the onscreen content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the downside, Apple brought the new displays so close to the case
edges that the new 1080p FaceTime HD camera (better videoconferencing
quality but no Center Stage support) lives in an iPhone-like notch that
cuts the Mac menu bar in half. Full-screen apps can avoid the notch.
Although the notch isn’t ideal, iPhone users seldom notice it after a
short while, and we expect the same will be true here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image8.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other negative for the new 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pro
models is weight. They’re both about 0.4 pounds (0.18 kg) heavier than
the models they replace, at 3.5 pounds (1.6 kg) for the 14-inch model
and 4.7 or 4.8 pounds (2.1 or 2.2 kg) for the 16-inch model—the M1 Max
configurations are a bit heavier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the notch and the weight, these are impressive new entries in
the Mac lineup, and we anticipate they’ll be well-received by users who
are happy to pay more for top-of-the-line machines. The 14-inch MacBook
Pro starts at $1999 and the 16-inch model at $2499. Numerous options
are available, so you can choose an M1 Pro or M1 Max for either size,
and pick from 16 GB, 32 GB, and 64 GB unified memory configurations.
When it comes to storage (which Apple says is also more than twice as
fast as previous SSDs), your choices are 512 GB, 1 TB, 2 TB, 4 TB, and 8
TB. Beware that the 8 TB SSD will cost you $2400.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211019Ne/image9.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t make informed recommendations about what options you should
choose until users start testing their real-world workflows against the
M1 Pro and M1 Max and see how much memory is really necessary. For now,
let your budget be your guide, and aim for an M1 Max if you work with
video. You can place orders with Apple now, but be warned that global
supply chain issues may mean waiting for some configurations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Last year, Apple started to transition Macs away from Intel processors to its custom M1 system-on-a-chip. The M1’s performance is stellar, but Apple has used it only in low-end models so far: the MacBook Air, 13-inch MacBook Pro, Mac mini, and new 24-inch iMac. For professionals looking for more power, Apple unveiled the future of high-end Macs at its October 18th Unleashed event.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Unleashed.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Unleashed.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Safari 15</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/safari/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Safari 15" /><published>2021-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Safari.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/safari/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features-to-try-or-not-in-safari-15&quot;&gt;New Features to Try (Or Not) in Safari 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with a new version of Safari in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, Apple has
released Safari 15 for macOS 11 Big Sur and macOS 10.15 Catalina. Why do
this before macOS 12 Monterey ships? Some of the browser’s new
capabilities—notably the Tab Groups feature—integrate it more deeply
into your Apple device experience by syncing across devices. So,
assuming you have Safari 15 on at least some of your devices, what’s
new, and is it any good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-tab-bar-interface&quot;&gt;New Tab Bar Interface&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Safari 15, Apple tried to minimize the tab bar interface to occupy
less screen real estate and stand out less from the content of Web pages
by co-opting the color of each page. Early betas were met with a litany
of complaints from testers, and Apple pulled back in the eventual
releases, offering settings that let you retain the old interface. How
that plays out varies between the iPhone, iPad, and Mac:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPhone:&lt;/strong&gt; Apple combined the address bar and tab bar into a single
set of controls at the bottom of the screen, where they’re easier to
reach with your thumb while working one-handed and where you can
swipe left and right to switch tabs. Plus, the status bar area at
the top of the screen takes on the color from the current site,
which isn’t necessarily a visual win. This is a huge change from the
controls appearing at the top, so if you don’t like it, go to
Settings &amp;gt; Safari and switch from Tab Bar (below left) to Single Tab
(below right). Turn off Allow Website Tinting (also below right) if
you don’t like the colorizing.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad:&lt;/strong&gt; Displays on the iPad are relatively small, so saving some
vertical space with the new Compact Tab Bar could be helpful.
However, since the tab bar automatically minimizes when you scroll
down a page, reducing its size when it’s visible isn’t as much of a
win as it might seem. And the colorized tab bar can be shockingly
bright. In Settings &amp;gt; Safari, you can choose between Compact Tab Bar
(below top) and Separate Tab Bar (below bottom); either way,
consider disabling Show Color in Tab Bar.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mac:&lt;/strong&gt; Laptop screens aren’t huge, and Safari doesn’t minimize its
tab bar when you scroll, as it does on the iPhone and iPad, so
saving some vertical space might be welcome on a smaller screen. But
the way the Compact layout embeds the address field inside a tab and
reduces the number of buttons you can see may perturb you (below
top). Once again, the colorized tab bar can be glaring. To revert to
something closer to the old look, in Safari &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Tabs,
select Separate for the tab layout (below bottom), and disable Show
Color in Tab Bar to keep the controls gray regardless of the site
color.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image4.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;voice-search&quot;&gt;Voice Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many searches, it’s easier to speak than type, and Apple has made
doing that even faster with Voice Search on the iPhone and iPad. Tap the
current tab to display the address field, tap the microphone button, and
speak instead of typing. As soon as you stop, Safari performs the
search. You can even navigate directly to a site by speaking its URL,
like “apple dot com.” Sadly, Apple didn’t extend this feature to the Mac
version of Safari 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tab-switcher&quot;&gt;Tab Switcher&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iOS 14 and earlier, Safari used a card stack metaphor for its tab
switcher (below left), which could make it hard to see what each tab
contained. In Safari in iOS 15, Apple took a cue from the iPad and Mac
versions of the app and moved to a grid interface for the tab switcher
(below right). You can drag the tab thumbnails around to organize them
and remove them by tapping an X button (weirdly located in the
upper-right corner) or swiping them left off-screen. You can also bring
up the option to close all open tabs by pressing and holding Done at the
lower right corner of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tab-groups&quot;&gt;Tab Groups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you struggle under the cognitive load of dozens of unrelated tabs,
the new Tab Groups feature might help. With it, you can collect tabs
into as many groups as you like and switch among them. You work with tab
groups in either the tab switcher interface (iPhone and iPad with the
Separate Tab Bar) or the sidebar (Mac and iPad with the Compact Tab
Bar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To open the tab switcher on the iPhone, tap the tab button in the lower-right corner of the
screen; on the iPad, tap the different-looking tab button in the upper-right corner. Once
you have the tab switcher open, tap X Tabs to reveal the Tab Groups
menu. To show the sidebar on either the iPad or the Mac, tap or click
the sidebar button in the upper-left corner of the
tab bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the Tab Groups menu or sidebar showing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To create a new tab group on the iPhone’s or iPad’s Tab Groups menu,
tap New Empty Tab Group, name it, and tap Save. In the sidebar on a
Mac or iPad, use the New Tab Group button at the top (or choose File &amp;gt;
New Empty Tab Group on the Mac). You can also use New Tab Group from
X Tabs to create a tab group from currently open tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To switch to a different tab group, tap it in the Tab Groups menu on
an iPhone or iPad, or access it from the sidebar on a Mac or iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To delete a tab group, swipe left on it in the Tab Groups menu or
sidebar to reveal a delete icon on an iPhone or iPad; on the Mac,
Control-click it and choose Delete.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image11.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shared-with-you&quot;&gt;Shared with You&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever gone spelunking through Messages to find a link someone sent you?
Safari 15’s new Shared with You feature should help. It automatically
collects all Web pages you receive in Messages into a new Shared with
You section of the Safari start page. On the iPad and Mac, there’s also
a Shared with You item in the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image12.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customizable-start-page&quot;&gt;Customizable Start Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the start page, if you want to customize which headings
appear and in what order, you can now do that on the iPhone and iPad.
(Choosing which headings appear has long been possible on the Mac by
clicking the little settings button in the lower-right corner, but
reordering isn’t possible there.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new tab to view the start page, scroll to the bottom, and tap
Edit. Then disable any headings you don’t want to see and drag the
remaining ones into your desired order. You can also choose among
several Apple-provided background images and have your start page
settings sync to your other devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Sa/image13.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-stuff&quot;&gt;Other Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two final new features may be welcome but probably won’t rock your
world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pull to refresh:&lt;/strong&gt; If you need to reload a Web page on the iPhone
or iPad, either you can tap the reload button in the address field
if it’s visible with your tab bar settings, or you can now just pull
down with your finger from the top of a page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTPS upgrade:&lt;/strong&gt; If you visit a website that supports encrypted
HTTPS but is also loading insecure content over unencrypted HTTP,
Safari will now ensure that you connect to it over HTTPS so your
entire connection is secure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it! Check out the new features in Safari 15 and let them
improve your browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">New Features to Try (Or Not) in Safari 15</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariiOS.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariiOS.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Forget Wi-Fi Networks</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/forget-wi-fi-networks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forget Wi-Fi Networks" /><published>2021-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Forget-Wi-Fi-Networks.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/forget-wi-fi-networks/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-it-comes-to-wi-fi-networks-sometimes-its-better-to-forget&quot;&gt;When It Comes to Wi-Fi Networks, Sometimes It’s Better to Forget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy, particularly when traveling, to end up connecting to a Wi-Fi
network that doesn’t provide Internet access, requires credentials you
don’t have, or lacks access to the network’s printer. Unfortunately,
once your iPhone, iPad, or Mac has connected to such a network, it may
reconnect to it later, causing consternation when things don’t work. The
solution? Whenever you realize a Wi-Fi network is worthless, forget it.
(The network, that is.) On the Mac, open System Preferences &amp;gt; Network &amp;gt; Wi-Fi &amp;gt; Advanced &amp;gt; Wi-Fi, select the network in the list (you don’t
have to be connected to it), click the – button, and click Remove. On
an iPhone or iPad, when you’re connected to the offending network, go to
Settings &amp;gt; Wi-Fi, tap the i button to the right of the current network,
and tap Forget This Network on the next screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001Fo/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">When It Comes to Wi-Fi Networks, Sometimes It’s Better to Forget</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSWiFi.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSWiFi.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>