<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://grovetech.co/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://grovetech.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2021-11-29T08:35:13-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/atom.xml</id><title type="html"> - Mac Support DC</title><subtitle>Grove Technologies - Washington DC's best Mac Support company for Digital Agencies, Creative Professionals &amp; Non Profits.</subtitle><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><entry><title type="html">macOS Safari Reverses Course, Reverts to Old Tab Interface</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/macos-safari-reverses-course,-reverts-to-old-tab-interface/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="macOS Safari Reverses Course, Reverts to Old Tab Interface" /><published>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/macOS-Safari-Reverses-Course,-Reverts-to-Old-Tab-Interface.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/macos-safari-reverses-course,-reverts-to-old-tab-interface/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;safari-151-reverses-course-reverts-to-old-tab-interface&quot;&gt;Safari 15.1 Reverses Course, Reverts to Old Tab Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the betas of Safari 15 on the Mac and iPad, Apple experimented with
a variety of interface tweaks related to tabs. By the time Safari 15
shipped, however, Apple had pulled back on the more radical changes from
the betas, offering the new Compact Tab Bar layout and colorized tab bar
as options. Even with the more traditional Separate Tab Bar layout,
however, tabs appeared as buttons above your favorites, a switch from
earlier versions of Safari. With Safari 15.1 in macOS and iPadOS 15.1,
Apple has reverted the Separate Tab Bar layout even further, making the
tabs look like, well, tabs, moving them below the favorites, and
eliminating the colorized tab bar (it remains an option in iOS 15.1).
The Compact Tab Bar option remains available for those who prefer it,
but if you’ve been feeling the sand shifting under your feet, it’s not
your imagination—tabs really did change in Safari 15.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101ma/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Safari 15.1 Reverses Course, Reverts to Old Tab Interface</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariTabChanges.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariTabChanges.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Live Text Digitizes Text in Photos in iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS 12 Monterey</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/live-text-digitizes-text-in-photos-in-ios-15,-ipados-15,-and-macos-12-monterey-/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live Text Digitizes Text in Photos in iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS 12 Monterey" /><published>2021-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Live-Text-Digitizes-Text-in-Photos-in-iOS-15,-iPadOS-15,-and-macOS-12-Monterey-.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/live-text-digitizes-text-in-photos-in-ios-15,-ipados-15,-and-macos-12-monterey-/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;live-text-digitizes-text-in-photos-in-ios-15-ipados-15-and-macos-12-monterey&quot;&gt;Live Text Digitizes Text in Photos in iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS 12 Monterey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most magical feature of Apple’s latest crop of operating
systems—iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS 12 Monterey—may be Live Text.
You’re probably familiar with the concept of &lt;em&gt;optical character
recognition&lt;/em&gt; (OCR), which turns all the text on a scanned page into
normal text you can select, copy, and edit. Live Text does exactly that
in Photos, Safari, and the Camera app, plus lets you search for text in
photos. And it does it in not just in English, but also Chinese, French,
German, Italian, Portuguese, and Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the incredible processing power of Apple’s recent devices,
this digitization of graphics to text takes place instantly—hence
“live” text. Apple says it works on any Mac that can run Monterey, but
on the iPhone and iPad, it requires a model with an A12 Bionic processor
or later, which means anything in this list (check your device in
Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; About &amp;gt; Model Name):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPhone XR, XS, XS Max, and later, including the iPhone SE (2nd
generation)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPad Pro 12.9-inch (3rd generation) and later&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPad Pro 11-inch&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPad Air (3rd generation) and later&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPad (8th generation) and later&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;iPad mini (5th generation) and later&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;live-text-in-photos&quot;&gt;Live Text in Photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main place you’ll use Live Text is in Photos. In iOS and iPadOS,
when viewing a picture containing text, touch and hold a bit of text
until it highlights in blue. (For text-intensive images, Photos displays
a Detect Text button in the lower-right corner; tap it to highlight
recognized text.) The familiar text popover then appears. Drag the blue
selection handles to adjust the selection as desired or tap Select All.
Then you’ll most likely want to copy the text, switch to another app,
and paste, though you can also do a Web search by tapping Look Up or
have the device read the text out loud by tapping Speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two quick tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Want to copy text from an app that doesn’t even let you select text?
Take a screenshot of the app and use Live Text to copy it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you have an animated Live Photo that contains text, touch and
hold the text to select it; touch and hold away from the text to
animate the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Monterey, move the pointer over the text so it turns to a text
selection cursor, then select the text, after which you can copy it as
you would any other text. You can also Control-click the selected text
to access Look Up or Translate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, text from Photos that Live Text has
recognized is indexed by the system-wide search. So when you pull down
from the middle of the Home screen and search, a Text Found in Photos
section shows images that contain the search text. Tap one to view it,
and note that there’s a Detect Text button in the preview that
identifies text you can select right there. Or tap the Photos button in
the lower-right corner to open the image in Photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;live-text-in-the-camera-app&quot;&gt;Live Text in the Camera App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to capture some text in the real world without
having a photo to store and later delete—getting an appliance’s model
or serial number is a perfect example. When Live Text detects text in
the Camera app’s viewfinder, it puts a faint yellow outline around it
and displays the Detect Text button. Tap the Detect Text button to
freeze and zoom the selection—it even rotates sideways text to be
readable—and then tap the text to select and copy it. Tap the Detect
Text button again when you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another way to use Live Text in conjunction with the iPhone or
iPad camera that’s useful if you need to insert a large amount of text
directly into a document. In an app that supports Live Text, like Notes,
tap in the text entry area and then tap the Scan Text button. A
viewfinder appears on the bottom half of the screen, with a yellow
outline around detected text, and the recognized text above. If that’s
what you want, tap the Insert button to put the text into your note or
document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;live-text-in-safari-and-other-apps&quot;&gt;Live Text in Safari and Other Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Apple integrated Live Text into its operating systems, it’s
available nearly anywhere you might see an image that contains text. For
instance, in Safari, you’re likely to run across such images, or you
might have embedded photos in Notes that contain text. Selecting text
using Live Text works exactly the same as in Photos—either touch and
hold on an iPhone or iPad, or just select the text on the Mac. And on
the Mac, Live Text even works when you select an image in the Finder and
press the Space bar to view it in Quick Look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Li/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-live-text-tricks&quot;&gt;Other Live Text Tricks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify types of data:&lt;/strong&gt; When Live Text recognizes text that
contains an email address, phone number, postal address, or date,
you can touch and hold it to bring up special options to send an
email, call the number, map the address, or make an event or
reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translate Live Text:&lt;/strong&gt; The Translate app in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15
is now a system-wide service, so it can translate any text you can
select, including text recognized by Live Text in a photo or in the
Camera app. Just select it and tap Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear Live Text:&lt;/strong&gt; If you rely on VoiceOver to help you navigate
your iPhone or iPad, note that you can leverage Live Text to get
VoiceOver to read text in your photos out loud. Go to Settings &amp;gt;
Accessibility &amp;gt; VoiceOver &amp;gt; VoiceOver Recognition and turn on Text
Recognition. Then, while viewing a photo, tap the text in the photo
to have VoiceOver read to you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may take a little while to remember that you can select and copy,
look up, or translate nearly any text you see in a picture—or in your
camera viewfinder—but once you’ve tried Live Text a few times, we’re
betting that you’ll find it surprisingly useful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Live Text Digitizes Text in Photos in iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS 12 Monterey</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-LiveText.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-LiveText.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Avoid Unusual Top-Level Domains in Custom Domain Names</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/avoid-unusual-top-level-domains-in-custom-domain-names/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Avoid Unusual Top-Level Domains in Custom Domain Names" /><published>2021-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Avoid-Unusual-Top-Level-Domains-in-Custom-Domain-Names.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/avoid-unusual-top-level-domains-in-custom-domain-names/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-unusual-top-level-domains-in-custom-domain-names&quot;&gt;Avoid Unusual Top-Level Domains in Custom Domain Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the heady dotcom days, when businesses were desperate to get a
short, memorable, easily typed .com domain? It quickly became difficult
to get what you wanted—so much so that deep-pocketed companies paid
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_most_expensive_domain_names&quot;&gt;exorbitant
sums&lt;/a&gt;
for just the right domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let’s make sure we’re all on the same page.
Domain names are necessary because computers on the Internet are all
identified by inscrutable numeric IP addresses. You can remember and
type apple.com easily; 184.31.17.21 not so much. Domain names have two
or more parts: the top-level domain (read from the end, such as com) and
the second-level domain (like apple), plus optional third-level domains
(which could give you support.apple.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the days of speculating in .com domains, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains&quot;&gt;hundreds of
additional top-level
domains&lt;/a&gt;
have been opened up, including domains from .aaa to .zone. There are now
top-level domains for .doctor, .florist, .lawyer, and many more,
including the general .xyz. It might be tempting to switch from the
awkward dewey-cheatham-howe.com to the shorter and more memorable
dch.lawyer. And even if there isn’t a profession-specific top-level
domain that works for you, you may think that if abc.xyz is good enough
for Google’s parent company Alphabet, surely it’s good enough for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, much as we appreciate the creativity and flexibility offered by
these alternative top-level domains, we’d like to dissuade you from
using one, if possible. Problems include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email deliverability:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re sending email using an
alternative top-level domain or including links to that domain, it’s
much more likely that your email will be considered spam by
receiving systems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMS deliverability:&lt;/strong&gt; Some SMS text message providers will
automatically delete messages containing URLs with alternative
top-level domains in an effort to protect their customers from
phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social media spam filtering:&lt;/strong&gt; As with SMS text messages, social
media posts that include URLs with alternative top-level domains may
be categorized as spam or as linking to a malicious site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firewall blocking:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/06/bad-men-at-work-please-dont-click/&quot;&gt;Abuse of alternative top-level
domains&lt;/a&gt;
has become so commonplace by scammers that some companies prevent
their employees from accessing websites using certain alternative
top-level domains at the firewall level.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User perception:&lt;/strong&gt; Although there’s no telling how anyone will
react to a particular top-level domain, people won’t think twice
about .com but might think .ooo seems sketchy. (We would.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it may not be possible to get the domain name you want in
.com. What to do? There are a few strategies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expand or abbreviate:&lt;/strong&gt; At this time, people mostly don’t see,
remember, or type domains apart from those that go with businesses
that do a lot of real-world advertising. So if you need to add or
subtract words (or letters) in your domain to find a unique one,
that can work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a country domain:&lt;/strong&gt; Two-letter top-level domains are
restricted for use by countries, so .us is for the United States,
.ca for Canada, and .au for Australia. Every country has different
rules for who can register them. For instance, it’s possible to get
a domain ending in .it (Italy) as long as you work through a
registrar that acts as your representative there. .io (British
Indian Ocean Territory) and .ai (Anguilla) are popular top-level
domains among tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stick with better, pricier alternatives:&lt;/strong&gt; Not all alternative
top-level domains are equally problematic. The classic .net and .org
are fine, and .biz isn’t bad. But how to determine that? When you’re
checking to see if a domain name is available, compare prices. For
instance, at one domain name registrar, iphonewhisperer.xyz costs
only $1 per year, whereas the iphonewhisperer.biz version is $4.98
per year, iphonewhisperer.net is $9.18 per year, and
iphonewhisperer.studio is $11.98 per year. The more you pay, the
less likely that domain has been abused by spammers and marked for
filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, when it comes to domain names, it’s best to be conservative
and stick with a top-level domain that won’t cause people or filters to
think twice. That’s probably .com, if you can make the rest of the name
work for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Avoid Unusual Top-Level Domains in Custom Domain Names</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-DomainName.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-DomainName.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple Provides Temporary iCloud Backup Space for New Device Transfers</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/apple-provides-temporary-icloud-backup-space-for-new-device-transfers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple Provides Temporary iCloud Backup Space for New Device Transfers" /><published>2021-11-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Apple-Provides-Temporary-iCloud-Backup-Space-for-New-Device-Transfers.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/apple-provides-temporary-icloud-backup-space-for-new-device-transfers/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-provides-temporary-icloud-backup-space-for-new-device-transfers&quot;&gt;Apple Provides Temporary iCloud Backup Space for New Device Transfers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you move from an old iPhone or iPad to a new one, the easiest
approach is often the Quick Start device-to-device transfer. But if that
doesn’t work, or if you have to give up one device before receiving the
other, iCloud Backup is a fine alternative. Fine, that is, if you have
enough iCloud storage space, which many people with the free 5 GB plan
do not. For devices running iOS 15 or iPadOS 15, Apple just introduced
the option to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-ca/HT212732&quot;&gt;[create a temporary iCloud
backup]{.ul}&lt;/a&gt; that’s larger
than the available space. Tap Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Transfer or Reset
&lt;em&gt;Device&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; Get Started to create the backup. You have 21 days (plus
another 21 if necessary) to restore that backup, and it sticks around
for another 7 days after you restore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ap/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Apple Provides Temporary iCloud Backup Space for New Device Transfers</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iCloudBackupTemp.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iCloudBackupTemp.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try" /><published>2021-11-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Need-to-Resize-Images-in-Various-Ways-Give-Preview-a-Try.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try&quot;&gt;Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even those of us who don’t work with graphics professionally often find
ourselves needing to resize images. Perhaps you have a large square
headshot, but the site to which you’re uploading requires it to be
exactly 100 by 100 pixels. Or maybe you have an iPhone 13 Pro photo
that’s 4032 by 3024, but you need the long side to be 1280 pixels and
the short side to be 800 pixels. You might even need to cut out an
800-by-600 rectangle from a much larger image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tasks are easily accomplished with professional graphics apps like
Photoshop, but you don’t need to pay for or learn Photoshop for a quick
resizing and cropping of an image. That’s because Preview, which is
built into macOS, can do many of these tasks with aplomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One note: You can resize images to be smaller with little or no loss of
quality, but you can’t make images bigger without them looking fuzzier
unless you employ specialized tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shrink-an-image-without-changing-aspect-ratio&quot;&gt;Shrink an Image without Changing Aspect Ratio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take our first example above. We have a square headshot that we
need to upload to an account, but the site won’t accept an image larger
than 100 pixels square. To shrink the image to the specified size, we’ll
first make a copy in the Finder or we’ll open the file in Preview and
choose File &amp;gt; Duplicate. Then, with the image open in Preview, we’ll
choose Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size, make sure “pixels” is chosen to the right
of the Width and Height fields, and enter 100 into the Width field.
Because Scale Proportionally is selected, Height automatically changes
to 100 to match. We’ll click OK to exit the dialog and then save the
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shrink-an-image-and-crop-to-different-dimensions&quot;&gt;Shrink an Image and Crop to Different Dimensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s move on to our second example above. We have a photo of some
home-baked bread loaves that we’ve taken with the iPhone, and we need to
resize it to 1280 by 800 pixels before uploading it to our food blog.
There are two problems: the image is much larger than we need to start,
and when we try resizing it to the desired pixel count in one dimension,
the other dimension is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start the same way we did before, by making a copy of the original
and in Preview choosing Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size. In the Image Dimensions
dialog, we’ll first type 1280 into the Width field. In this example,
doing that causes the Height field to change to 752, which is too small
(below left). Remember, shrinking images is easy and works well, but
expanding them is hard. So instead, we’ll type 800 into the Height
field, which causes the Width field to change to 1361 (below right).
That’s good; we’ll click OK to resize the image. It will look small, but
we can zoom it back to the window size by choosing View &amp;gt; Zoom to Fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image3.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next step, we need to get the image width down from 1361 to 1280
pixels, which we do by cropping. Choose Edit &amp;gt; Select All (or just
press Command-A), and notice that there’s a selection rectangle around
the entire image, with blue drag handles in the middle of each side and
at each corner. We’ll need to take some off each side to keep the loaves
centered, so we’ll drag the left side in a little to start. If you have
trouble grabbing the blue drag handles instead of the edge of Preview’s
window, choose View &amp;gt; Zoom Out to zoom out one step and separate the
handles from the window edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we’ll drag the right side in. Notice that as we drag, Preview
displays the image dimensions in a little lozenge (at the right in the
screenshot)—we’ve stopped at 1280. Since we’re moving only the edges,
only the width changes—resizing from the corners would be much harder
because both dimensions would change simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tip. If you’ve gotten the selection rectangle to 1280 by 800, but
the content under it isn’t centered as you’d like, press and hold the
left or right arrow key to move the selection rectangle to the left or
right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have the selection rectangle at the right size and in the right
place, we’ll choose Tools &amp;gt; Crop to discard the image content outside
the selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extract-a-portion-of-an-image-with-specific-dimensions&quot;&gt;Extract a Portion of an Image with Specific Dimensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our final example, let’s assume that we have a large picture of
cherry tomatoes, and we need to cut out just the black tomatoes for a
Web page that requires an 800-by-600 image. Once again, the image is too
large, but the trickier problem is that we only need a small portion of
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by dragging out a selection rectangle that’s roughly 800 by
600, using Preview’s measurement lozenge. All we’re doing here is
getting a sense of what the shape of 800 by 600 looks like. Then we make
another selection around the black cherry tomatoes that’s roughly the
same aspect ratio, wider than it is tall. The details don’t matter much
at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to crop the photo to the selection with Tools &amp;gt; Crop.
Then we choose Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size and set the Width field to 800 to
get the width correct. That reveals that the height of our rough crop
was slightly too large, at 630 pixels. We’ll click OK to resize the
image to those dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll use the same technique we did in the example above, with
Select All, dragging the top handle down until the dimensions are 800 by
600, and then using Tools &amp;gt; Crop to discard the extra content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Ne/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can do a lot with just three basic techniques in
Preview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Tools &amp;gt; Adjust Size to resize the entire image&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dragging out selection rectangles while paying attention to the
measurements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Tools &amp;gt; Crop to get rid of content outside the selection
rectangle&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won’t pretend that Preview is the ultimate graphics tool, but it’s
capable, easy to use, and on every Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More" /><published>2021-11-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/Use-Visual-Look-Up-in-Photos-in-iOS-15-to-Identify-Plants,-Pets,-and-More.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants-pets-and-more&quot;&gt;Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to identify a plant, flower, or pet breed, or find
out what that famous painting is called? Us too. In iOS 15 and iPadOS
15, Apple added a new AI-driven feature called Visual Look Up that
provides more information about photos of plants, flowers, pets, books,
artworks, and landmarks. When you’re viewing a photo, swipe up or tap
the sparkle-badged info button ➊ to see metadata about the image (camera
model, image details, location, and more) and then tap Look Up to learn
more ➋. Depending on the item recognized, it will suggest Wikipedia
articles, similar images from the Web, websites, bookstores, map
locations, and more. Tap a suggestion to switch to Safari or another app
for details. (If the info button doesn’t have the sparkle badge, Visual
Look Up hasn’t identified anything in the photo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Us/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021" /><published>2021-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/The-Best-Apple-Related-Gifts-for-2021.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021&quot;&gt;The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem early to start thinking about the holiday shopping season,
but with the global supply chain suffering pandemic-related slowdowns,
there’s no telling how long it will take to get something you order
today. Apple has generally done a good job of managing its supply chain
issues, but even still, if you want to make sure you have an Apple
something for that special someone, we recommend buying it soon. Here
are our recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airtag&quot;&gt;AirTag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know someone who’s always misplacing their keys, purse, or
backpack? Apple’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airtag/&quot;&gt;AirTag&lt;/a&gt;
tracker is the perfect gift for such a person. Attach one to a keyring
(with a separate $29 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYY3ZM/A/airtag-loop-pink-citrus&quot;&gt;AirTag
Loop&lt;/a&gt;
or $39 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM043ZM/A/airtag-leather-loop-baltic-blue&quot;&gt;AirTag Leather
Loop&lt;/a&gt;)
or drop it in a bag, and from then on, the person can use the Find My
app to see where they left their stuff. Support for ultra-wideband
enables precision finding with an iPhone 11 or later—with earlier
iPhones, the detected location won’t be quite so precise. AirTag uses
the Find My network, so even if the item is far away, passing Apple
devices that detect it can securely share its location with you. One
AirTag costs $29, or you can get a pack of four for $99. You can even
have Apple personalize each AirTag with custom text and emoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airpods-and-airpods-pro&quot;&gt;AirPods and AirPods Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s wireless earbuds remain popular, and the company just released
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-3rd-generation/&quot;&gt;third-generation
AirPods&lt;/a&gt; to
supplement the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-2nd-generation/&quot;&gt;second-generation
AirPods&lt;/a&gt; and the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/airpods-pro/&quot;&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;. All three make
excellent gifts. The second-generation AirPods cost $129, have a
relatively long stalk, and boast up to 5 hours of listening on one
charge. The $179 third-generation AirPods shrink the stalk, switch to a
force sensor for controls, add support for spatial audio with dynamic
head tracking, feature sweat and water resistance, have a MagSafe
wireless charging case, and last up to 6 hours on a single charge. For
$249, the AirPods Pro include the features of the third-generation
AirPods and add silicone ear tips and active noise cancellation with
optional transparency mode, but they have only 4.5 hours of listening
time. All three have charging cases, support Hey Siri commands, and
automatically switch between Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homepod-mini&quot;&gt;HomePod mini&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Apple discontinued the full-size HomePod, which
wasn’t a big hit at its relatively high price of $299. However, the
$99 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/homepod-mini/&quot;&gt;HomePod mini&lt;/a&gt; remains
available, and Apple is now selling it in five colors, with blue,
orange, and yellow joining white and black. (The new colors will become
available at some point in November.) The grapefruit-sized HomePod mini
may be small, but it produces great sound for its size, and it can do
pretty much everything the larger HomePod could do. You can control it
entirely via Siri, pair two for stereo sound, use it as a hub for your
HomeKit home automation accessories, and even have it play the sound
from your Apple TV. Put a HomePod mini in different rooms in the house,
and you can use Intercom to communicate with family members using your
voice. If you’re giving it as a gift, remember that it’s best when
paired with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-music/&quot;&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;
subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ipad-and-ipad-mini&quot;&gt;iPad and iPad mini&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to give an iPad as a gift, you have a lot of choice.
The top-of-the-line &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-pro/&quot;&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;
may be overkill for most given its power and price—$799 for the
11-inch model and $1099 for the 12.9-inch model. But the
fourth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-air/&quot;&gt;iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;,
which starts at $599, provides sufficient power for even the most
intensive tasks, especially when coupled with a second-generation
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-pencil/&quot;&gt;Apple Pencil&lt;/a&gt; ($129) and
either a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;
($299) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Smart Keyboard
Folio&lt;/a&gt; ($179).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those possibilities seem pricey for an iPad that’s destined for a kid
or an adult with basic needs, look no further than the new
ninth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-10.2/&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, which
remains a bargain at $329. It works with the first-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-pencil/&quot;&gt;Apple
Pencil&lt;/a&gt; ($99), and those who
need to write can add the $159 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Smart
Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, don’t
forget the sixth-generation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipad-mini/&quot;&gt;iPad
mini&lt;/a&gt;, which benefited from a
major redesign back in September. It’s now more like a diminutive
version of the iPad Air, with more colors and a squared-off industrial
design compatible with the second-generation Apple Pencil. It’s $499,
and if you need a keyboard, you’ll have to look to a third-party
manufacturer or use a standard Bluetooth wireless keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apple-watch-gift-certificate&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Gift Certificate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but far from least, we love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/watch/&quot;&gt;Apple
Watch&lt;/a&gt;, and it would seem to make a
great gift. However, we urge caution. Apple provides a dizzying number
of options for case size, material, and color, plus the band and color,
making it difficult to know what would be most appreciated. So we’d
encourage giving a certificate that’s good for a conversation about what
to purchase. Then sit down with the recipient to run through all the
decisions in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/studio&quot;&gt;Apple Watch
Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three options this year: the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-6/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Series
7&lt;/a&gt; (starting at
$399), last year’s less expensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-se/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch
SE&lt;/a&gt; (starting at $279), or
the much older &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-3/&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Series
3&lt;/a&gt; (starting at
$199). Get the Series 7 if you want an Always-On Display, blood oxygen
sensor, and ECG capabilities—it also boasts a larger screen than last
year’s Series 6 while remaining compatible with all the bands. The Apple
Watch SE lacks the Series 7’s advanced sensors and has a slightly
smaller screen size, but it still provides the compass, altimeter, and
fall detection features. The screen on the Series 3 is smaller yet, and
it lacks a number of key features. Unless keeping the cost to a minimum
is essential, we have a hard time recommending the Series 3—it’s
getting too old. Apple has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/watch/compare/&quot;&gt;helpful comparison
tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Th/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that we didn’t include any Macs in this article.
They are worthy gifts, but they’re quite a bit more expensive and more
difficult to select without extensive discussion of the recipient’s
needs. Let us know if you need help choosing the right Mac for someone
on your list, but we’re partial to the M1-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/macbook-air/&quot;&gt;MacBook
Air&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/imac-24/&quot;&gt;24-inch
iMac&lt;/a&gt; for many users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing" /><published>2021-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/With-Apple-Watch-Faces,-Too-Much-Choice-Can-Be-Confusing.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;with-apple-watch-faces-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing&quot;&gt;With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch has a lot to offer older people, including heart rate
monitoring, atrial fibrillation detection, fall detection, and
electrocardiogram recording. But if you are—or are helping someone who
is—of the generation where watches once did nothing beyond telling the
time, too many options can be overwhelming. Adding to the confusion is
how easy it is to create and accidentally swipe between multiple watch
faces, making it so the Apple Watch suddenly looks and works completely
differently. If that’s an issue, use the Watch app to delete all but the
preferred watch face. In Watch &amp;gt; My Watch, tap Edit to the right of My
Faces ➊, tap the red delete button next to a face ➋, and then tap Remove
➌.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211101Wi/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iPadOS Multitasking</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPadOS Multitasking" /><published>2021-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/iPadOS-Multitasking.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-radically-improved-multitasking-in-ipados-15-heres-how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Apple Radically Improved Multitasking in iPadOS 15. Here’s How to Use It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multitasking has long been a mess on the iPad, not so much because it
didn’t work but because it was tough to memorize the secret swipes
necessary to put multiple apps into Split View, work with multiple
windows in apps that supported them, and hide and show what you wanted
in Slide Over. In iPadOS 15, Apple hasn’t changed the underlying
multitasking capabilities much, but it has made them far more
discoverable with onscreen controls and tips that supplement the
previous gestures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-multitasking-menu&quot;&gt;Use the Multitasking Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most important is the new multitasking menu button that appears in the
top center of every app, represented by •••. Tap it to reveal a control
with three options—Full Screen, Split View, and Slide Over—and then
tap one of those to put the current app into that mode. From left:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Screen:&lt;/strong&gt; When only a single app is showing, the leftmost
button is selected. When you have an app in Split View or Slide
Over, tap the Full Screen button to make that app the only one
onscreen.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Split View:&lt;/strong&gt; Tap the middle button to shove the current app to
the left edge of the screen, revealing the Home screen and the Dock.
A little lozenge replaces the multitasking menu, telling you that
you’re working with Split View and to choose another app. Tap any
other app to open it (on the right side) with the current app (on
the left side), and remember that you can resize each app using the
handle on the black bar in the middle.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide Over:&lt;/strong&gt; In the current app window, tap the rightmost button
to push the app to the side of the screen, again revealing the Home
screen and the Dock and showing a lozenge that tells you that you’re
working with Slide Over and to choose another app. Tap any other to
open it full screen but with the current app floating above it in
Slide Over mode, and remember that you can hide the Slide Over app
easily by swiping it to the right.
&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-app-switcher&quot;&gt;Use the App Switcher&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple also made it much easier to see and manage your Split View
combinations by using the App Switcher. Once you go into it by swiping
up from the bottom of the screen (or double-pressing the Home button, if
your iPad has one), you have several multitasking-related options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch among apps:&lt;/strong&gt; Tap any app, Split View combination, or Slide
Over app (located on the right side of the App Switcher) to switch
to it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a Split View:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag any app or window onto another one to
combine them into a Split View (as is shown with Drive and Docs
below). Before you start to drag, pause for a moment to pick up the
app; drag until the items turn into icon-emblazoned gray rectangles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replace a Split View app:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag any app or window onto the left
or right side of a Split View combination to replace that app or
window.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Break a Split View combination:&lt;/strong&gt; Drag the left or right side of a
Split View combination off until it displays as a full-screen
thumbnail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the screenshot above, note the red arrow pointing to the little
stacked square icons above the Safari Split View windows. Those indicate
that the app in question has multiple windows. Tap the icon to display
just that app’s windows in the App Switcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-shelf&quot;&gt;Use the Shelf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The App Switcher may make it easier to see and switch among multiple
windows in apps, but another new multitasking feature, the Shelf, is
even more useful. When you use the Dock or a search to open an app with
multiple windows available, the Shelf displays them all at the bottom of
the screen. The Shelf doesn’t appear when you switch to an app using the
App Switcher or four-finger swipe, but you can bring it up at any time
by tapping the multitasking menu button at the top of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re looking at items on the Shelf, tap one to switch to it. You
can also swipe up on windows on the Shelf to close them. As soon as you
tap anywhere else in the app to start working, the Shelf disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-center-windows&quot;&gt;Use Center Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In at least some apps with sidebars, such as Mail and Notes, you can now
open an item like a message or a note in its own window in the center of
the screen. That’s useful for previewing the full content of the item,
and you can swipe down on the multitasking menu button to put the window
on the Shelf, which keeps it available for quick reference while you
work on something else. To create a center window, touch and hold the
item in the sidebar and then tap Open in New Window. To close it, tap
Close or swipe up on its Shelf thumbnail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image8.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-multitasking-keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Use the Multitasking Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seriously interested in using multitasking on an iPad, you’re
probably also working with a physical keyboard much of the time. In
iPadOS 15, Apple added a useful set of keyboard shortcuts that you can
learn about by pressing and holding the Globe key and then tapping the
Multitasking tab at the bottom. It may take a little while to
internalize the shortcuts, but if you do most of your work on an iPad,
you will probably find the effort worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image9.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like the idea of multitasking on the iPad but have never been
able to remember all the necessary gestures, iPadOS 15’s changes will be
welcome. Give them a try—we think they finally make multitasking
obvious enough for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Apple Radically Improved Multitasking in iPadOS 15. Here’s How to Use It</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iPhone 13 Upgrade Quick Start</title><link href="https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPhone 13 Upgrade Quick Start" /><published>2021-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://grovetech.co/blog/iPhone-upgrade-Quick-Start.docx</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-migrating-to-a-new-iphone-or-ipad-try-quick-start-first&quot;&gt;When Migrating to a New iPhone or iPad, Try Quick Start First&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a new iPhone or iPad—congratulations! When transferring your
data to the new device, you have three options: &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210216&quot;&gt;Quick
Start&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204184&quot;&gt;iCloud
backup&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204184&quot;&gt;Mac
backup&lt;/a&gt;. All will work,
but they don’t quite provide the same end result (particularly if you
didn’t encrypt your Mac backup). Our advice—backed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2021/09/24/how-to-set-up-a-new-iphone-or-ipad&quot;&gt;this post from
Apple expert John
Gruber&lt;/a&gt;—is
to try Quick Start first because it transfers everything directly from
your old device to your new one, maintaining app logins in most cases
and allowing you to transfer your Apple Watch pairing. It may seem like
it’s taking a long time before you can use the device, but it’s worth it
to avoid logging in to numerous apps and unpairing and repairing your
Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blog Photo&quot; src=&quot;https://grovetech.co/assets/img/blog/2021/20211001iP/image2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded m-2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Brown</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="MacOS" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">When Migrating to a New iPhone or iPad, Try Quick Start First</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>