<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Grove Technologies App</title>
        <link>https://grovetech.co</link>
        <description>A feed for the iOS Grove Technologies App</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>2021-11-14 22:16:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>2021-11-14 22:16:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://grovetech.co/app/out.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Need to Resize Images in Various Ways? Give Preview a Try

Even those of us who don’t work with graphics professionally often find
ourselves needing to resize images. Perhaps you have a large square
headshot, but the site to which you’re uploading requires it to be
exactly 100 by 100 pixels. Or maybe you have an iPhone 13 Pro photo
that’s 4032 by 3024, but you need the long side to be 1280 pixels and
the short side to be 800 pixels. You might even need to cut out an
800-by-600 rectangle from a much larger image.

These tasks are easily accomplished with professional graphics apps like
Photoshop, but you don’t need to pay for or learn Photoshop for a quick
resizing and cropping of an image. That’s because Preview, which is
built into macOS, can do many of these tasks with aplomb.

One note: You can resize images to be smaller with little or no loss of
quality, but you can’t make images bigger without them looking fuzzier
unless you employ specialized tools.

Shrink an Image without Changing Aspect Ratio

Let’s take our first example above. We have a square headshot that we
need to upload to an account, but the site won’t accept an image larger
than 100 pixels square. To shrink the image to the specified size, we’ll
first make a copy in the Finder or we’ll open the file in Preview and
choose File  Duplicate. Then, with the image open in Preview, we’ll
choose Tools  Adjust Size, make sure “pixels” is chosen to the right
of the Width and Height fields, and enter 100 into the Width field.
Because Scale Proportionally is selected, Height automatically changes
to 100 to match. We’ll click OK to exit the dialog and then save the
file.



Shrink an Image and Crop to Different Dimensions

Let’s move on to our second example above. We have a photo of some
home-baked bread loaves that we’ve taken with the iPhone, and we need to
resize it to 1280 by 800 pixels before uploading it to our food blog.
There are two problems: the image is much larger than we need to start,
and when we try resizing it to the desired pixel count in one dimension,
the other dimension is wrong.

We’ll start the same way we did before, by making a copy of the original
and in Preview choosing Tools  Adjust Size. In the Image Dimensions
dialog, we’ll first type 1280 into the Width field. In this example,
doing that causes the Height field to change to 752, which is too small
(below left). Remember, shrinking images is easy and works well, but
expanding them is hard. So instead, we’ll type 800 into the Height
field, which causes the Width field to change to 1361 (below right).
That’s good; we’ll click OK to resize the image. It will look small, but
we can zoom it back to the window size by choosing View  Zoom to Fit.



For the next step, we need to get the image width down from 1361 to 1280
pixels, which we do by cropping. Choose Edit  Select All (or just
press Command-A), and notice that there’s a selection rectangle around
the entire image, with blue drag handles in the middle of each side and
at each corner. We’ll need to take some off each side to keep the loaves
centered, so we’ll drag the left side in a little to start. If you have
trouble grabbing the blue drag handles instead of the edge of Preview’s
window, choose View  Zoom Out to zoom out one step and separate the
handles from the window edges.



Next, we’ll drag the right side in. Notice that as we drag, Preview
displays the image dimensions in a little lozenge (at the right in the
screenshot)—we’ve stopped at 1280. Since we’re moving only the edges,
only the width changes—resizing from the corners would be much harder
because both dimensions would change simultaneously.

One tip. If you’ve gotten the selection rectangle to 1280 by 800, but
the content under it isn’t centered as you’d like, press and hold the
left or right arrow key to move the selection rectangle to the left or
right.

Once we have the selection rectangle at the right size and in the right
place, we’ll choose Tools  Crop to discard the image content outside
the selection.

Extract a Portion of an Image with Specific Dimensions

For our final example, let’s assume that we have a large picture of
cherry tomatoes, and we need to cut out just the black tomatoes for a
Web page that requires an 800-by-600 image. Once again, the image is too
large, but the trickier problem is that we only need a small portion of
it.

We’ll start by dragging out a selection rectangle that’s roughly 800 by
600, using Preview’s measurement lozenge. All we’re doing here is
getting a sense of what the shape of 800 by 600 looks like. Then we make
another selection around the black cherry tomatoes that’s roughly the
same aspect ratio, wider than it is tall. The details don’t matter much
at this point.



The next step is to crop the photo to the selection with Tools  Crop.
Then we choose Tools  Adjust Size and set the Width field to 800 to
get the width correct. That reveals that the height of our rough crop
was slightly too large, at 630 pixels. We’ll click OK to resize the
image to those dimensions.



Finally, we’ll use the same technique we did in the example above, with
Select All, dragging the top handle down until the dimensions are 800 by
600, and then using Tools  Crop to discard the extra content.



As you can see, you can do a lot with just three basic techniques in
Preview:


  
    Using Tools  Adjust Size to resize the entire image
  
  
    Dragging out selection rectangles while paying attention to the
measurements
  
  
    Using Tools  Crop to get rid of content outside the selection
rectangle
  


We won’t pretend that Preview is the ultimate graphics tool, but it’s
capable, easy to use, and on every Mac.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Resize.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/need-to-resize-images-in-various-ways-give-preview-a-try/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Use Visual Look Up in Photos in iOS 15 to Identify Plants, Pets, and More

Have you ever wanted to identify a plant, flower, or pet breed, or find
out what that famous painting is called? Us too. In iOS 15 and iPadOS
15, Apple added a new AI-driven feature called Visual Look Up that
provides more information about photos of plants, flowers, pets, books,
artworks, and landmarks. When you’re viewing a photo, swipe up or tap
the sparkle-badged info button ➊ to see metadata about the image (camera
model, image details, location, and more) and then tap Look Up to learn
more ➋. Depending on the item recognized, it will suggest Wikipedia
articles, similar images from the Web, websites, bookstores, map
locations, and more. Tap a suggestion to switch to Safari or another app
for details. (If the info button doesn’t have the sparkle badge, Visual
Look Up hasn’t identified anything in the photo.)


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPhoneVisualLookup.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/use-visual-look-up-in-photos-in-ios-15-to-identify-plants,-pets,-and-more/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ The Best Apple-Related Gifts for 2021

It may seem early to start thinking about the holiday shopping season,
but with the global supply chain suffering pandemic-related slowdowns,
there’s no telling how long it will take to get something you order
today. Apple has generally done a good job of managing its supply chain
issues, but even still, if you want to make sure you have an Apple
something for that special someone, we recommend buying it soon. Here
are our recommendations.

AirTag

Do you know someone who’s always misplacing their keys, purse, or
backpack? Apple’s new AirTag
tracker is the perfect gift for such a person. Attach one to a keyring
(with a separate $29 AirTag
Loop
or $39 AirTag Leather
Loop)
or drop it in a bag, and from then on, the person can use the Find My
app to see where they left their stuff. Support for ultra-wideband
enables precision finding with an iPhone 11 or later—with earlier
iPhones, the detected location won’t be quite so precise. AirTag uses
the Find My network, so even if the item is far away, passing Apple
devices that detect it can securely share its location with you. One
AirTag costs $29, or you can get a pack of four for $99. You can even
have Apple personalize each AirTag with custom text and emoji.



AirPods and AirPods Pro

Apple’s wireless earbuds remain popular, and the company just released
the third-generation
AirPods to
supplement the second-generation
AirPods and the
AirPods Pro. All three make
excellent gifts. The second-generation AirPods cost $129, have a
relatively long stalk, and boast up to 5 hours of listening on one
charge. The $179 third-generation AirPods shrink the stalk, switch to a
force sensor for controls, add support for spatial audio with dynamic
head tracking, feature sweat and water resistance, have a MagSafe
wireless charging case, and last up to 6 hours on a single charge. For
$249, the AirPods Pro include the features of the third-generation
AirPods and add silicone ear tips and active noise cancellation with
optional transparency mode, but they have only 4.5 hours of listening
time. All three have charging cases, support Hey Siri commands, and
automatically switch between Apple devices.



HomePod mini

Earlier this year, Apple discontinued the full-size HomePod, which
wasn’t a big hit at its relatively high price of $299. However, the
$99 HomePod mini remains
available, and Apple is now selling it in five colors, with blue,
orange, and yellow joining white and black. (The new colors will become
available at some point in November.) The grapefruit-sized HomePod mini
may be small, but it produces great sound for its size, and it can do
pretty much everything the larger HomePod could do. You can control it
entirely via Siri, pair two for stereo sound, use it as a hub for your
HomeKit home automation accessories, and even have it play the sound
from your Apple TV. Put a HomePod mini in different rooms in the house,
and you can use Intercom to communicate with family members using your
voice. If you’re giving it as a gift, remember that it’s best when
paired with an Apple Music
subscription.



iPad and iPad mini

If you’re looking to give an iPad as a gift, you have a lot of choice.
The top-of-the-line iPad Pro
may be overkill for most given its power and price—$799 for the
11-inch model and $1099 for the 12.9-inch model. But the
fourth-generation iPad Air,
which starts at $599, provides sufficient power for even the most
intensive tasks, especially when coupled with a second-generation
Apple Pencil ($129) and
either a Magic Keyboard
($299) or Smart Keyboard
Folio ($179).

If those possibilities seem pricey for an iPad that’s destined for a kid
or an adult with basic needs, look no further than the new
ninth-generation iPad, which
remains a bargain at $329. It works with the first-generation Apple
Pencil ($99), and those who
need to write can add the $159 Smart
Keyboard. Finally, don’t
forget the sixth-generation iPad
mini, which benefited from a
major redesign back in September. It’s now more like a diminutive
version of the iPad Air, with more colors and a squared-off industrial
design compatible with the second-generation Apple Pencil. It’s $499,
and if you need a keyboard, you’ll have to look to a third-party
manufacturer or use a standard Bluetooth wireless keyboard.



Apple Watch Gift Certificate

Last but far from least, we love the Apple
Watch, and it would seem to make a
great gift. However, we urge caution. Apple provides a dizzying number
of options for case size, material, and color, plus the band and color,
making it difficult to know what would be most appreciated. So we’d
encourage giving a certificate that’s good for a conversation about what
to purchase. Then sit down with the recipient to run through all the
decisions in the Apple Watch
Studio.

There are three options this year: the new Apple Watch Series
7 (starting at
$399), last year’s less expensive Apple Watch
SE (starting at $279), or
the much older Apple Watch Series
3 (starting at
$199). Get the Series 7 if you want an Always-On Display, blood oxygen
sensor, and ECG capabilities—it also boasts a larger screen than last
year’s Series 6 while remaining compatible with all the bands. The Apple
Watch SE lacks the Series 7’s advanced sensors and has a slightly
smaller screen size, but it still provides the compass, altimeter, and
fall detection features. The screen on the Series 3 is smaller yet, and
it lacks a number of key features. Unless keeping the cost to a minimum
is essential, we have a hard time recommending the Series 3—it’s
getting too old. Apple has a helpful comparison
tool.



You may have noticed that we didn’t include any Macs in this article.
They are worthy gifts, but they’re quite a bit more expensive and more
difficult to select without extensive discussion of the recipient’s
needs. Let us know if you need help choosing the right Mac for someone
on your list, but we’re partial to the M1-based MacBook
Air and 24-inch
iMac for many users.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleGiftGuide.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/the-best-apple-related-gifts-for-2021/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ With Apple Watch Faces, Too Much Choice Can Be Confusing

The Apple Watch has a lot to offer older people, including heart rate
monitoring, atrial fibrillation detection, fall detection, and
electrocardiogram recording. But if you are—or are helping someone who
is—of the generation where watches once did nothing beyond telling the
time, too many options can be overwhelming. Adding to the confusion is
how easy it is to create and accidentally swipe between multiple watch
faces, making it so the Apple Watch suddenly looks and works completely
differently. If that’s an issue, use the Watch app to delete all but the
preferred watch face. In Watch  My Watch, tap Edit to the right of My
Faces ➊, tap the red delete button next to a face ➋, and then tap Remove
➌.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-AppleWatchFace.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/with-apple-watch-faces,-too-much-choice-can-be-confusing/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>iPadOS Multitasking</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Apple Radically Improved Multitasking in iPadOS 15. Here’s How to Use It

Multitasking has long been a mess on the iPad, not so much because it
didn’t work but because it was tough to memorize the secret swipes
necessary to put multiple apps into Split View, work with multiple
windows in apps that supported them, and hide and show what you wanted
in Slide Over. In iPadOS 15, Apple hasn’t changed the underlying
multitasking capabilities much, but it has made them far more
discoverable with onscreen controls and tips that supplement the
previous gestures.

Use the Multitasking Menu

Most important is the new multitasking menu button that appears in the
top center of every app, represented by •••. Tap it to reveal a control
with three options—Full Screen, Split View, and Slide Over—and then
tap one of those to put the current app into that mode. From left:


  
    Full Screen: When only a single app is showing, the leftmost
button is selected. When you have an app in Split View or Slide
Over, tap the Full Screen button to make that app the only one
onscreen.

  
  
    Split View: Tap the middle button to shove the current app to
the left edge of the screen, revealing the Home screen and the Dock.
A little lozenge replaces the multitasking menu, telling you that
you’re working with Split View and to choose another app. Tap any
other app to open it (on the right side) with the current app (on
the left side), and remember that you can resize each app using the
handle on the black bar in the middle.

  
  
    Slide Over: In the current app window, tap the rightmost button
to push the app to the side of the screen, again revealing the Home
screen and the Dock and showing a lozenge that tells you that you’re
working with Slide Over and to choose another app. Tap any other to
open it full screen but with the current app floating above it in
Slide Over mode, and remember that you can hide the Slide Over app
easily by swiping it to the right.

  


Use the App Switcher

Apple also made it much easier to see and manage your Split View
combinations by using the App Switcher. Once you go into it by swiping
up from the bottom of the screen (or double-pressing the Home button, if
your iPad has one), you have several multitasking-related options:


  
    Switch among apps: Tap any app, Split View combination, or Slide
Over app (located on the right side of the App Switcher) to switch
to it.
  
  
    Make a Split View: Drag any app or window onto another one to
combine them into a Split View (as is shown with Drive and Docs
below). Before you start to drag, pause for a moment to pick up the
app; drag until the items turn into icon-emblazoned gray rectangles.
  
  
    Replace a Split View app: Drag any app or window onto the left
or right side of a Split View combination to replace that app or
window.
  
  
    Break a Split View combination: Drag the left or right side of a
Split View combination off until it displays as a full-screen
thumbnail.
  




In the screenshot above, note the red arrow pointing to the little
stacked square icons above the Safari Split View windows. Those indicate
that the app in question has multiple windows. Tap the icon to display
just that app’s windows in the App Switcher.



Use the Shelf

The App Switcher may make it easier to see and switch among multiple
windows in apps, but another new multitasking feature, the Shelf, is
even more useful. When you use the Dock or a search to open an app with
multiple windows available, the Shelf displays them all at the bottom of
the screen. The Shelf doesn’t appear when you switch to an app using the
App Switcher or four-finger swipe, but you can bring it up at any time
by tapping the multitasking menu button at the top of the screen.

When you’re looking at items on the Shelf, tap one to switch to it. You
can also swipe up on windows on the Shelf to close them. As soon as you
tap anywhere else in the app to start working, the Shelf disappears.



Use Center Windows

In at least some apps with sidebars, such as Mail and Notes, you can now
open an item like a message or a note in its own window in the center of
the screen. That’s useful for previewing the full content of the item,
and you can swipe down on the multitasking menu button to put the window
on the Shelf, which keeps it available for quick reference while you
work on something else. To create a center window, touch and hold the
item in the sidebar and then tap Open in New Window. To close it, tap
Close or swipe up on its Shelf thumbnail.



Use the Multitasking Keyboard Shortcuts

If you’re seriously interested in using multitasking on an iPad, you’re
probably also working with a physical keyboard much of the time. In
iPadOS 15, Apple added a useful set of keyboard shortcuts that you can
learn about by pressing and holding the Globe key and then tapping the
Multitasking tab at the bottom. It may take a little while to
internalize the shortcuts, but if you do most of your work on an iPad,
you will probably find the effort worthwhile.



If you like the idea of multitasking on the iPad but have never been
able to remember all the necessary gestures, iPadOS 15’s changes will be
welcome. Give them a try—we think they finally make multitasking
obvious enough for everyone.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iPadOSMulti.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/ipados-multitasking/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>iPhone 13 Upgrade Quick Start</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ When Migrating to a New iPhone or iPad, Try Quick Start First

You have a new iPhone or iPad—congratulations! When transferring your
data to the new device, you have three options: Quick
Start, an iCloud
backup, or a Mac
backup. All will work,
but they don’t quite provide the same end result (particularly if you
didn’t encrypt your Mac backup). Our advice—backed by this post from
Apple expert John
Gruber—is
to try Quick Start first because it transfers everything directly from
your old device to your new one, maintaining app logins in most cases
and allowing you to transfer your Apple Watch pairing. It may seem like
it’s taking a long time before you can use the device, but it’s worth it
to avoid logging in to numerous apps and unpairing and repairing your
Apple Watch.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-QuickStart.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/iphone-upgrade-quick-start/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>iMessages not delivered</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Messages Not Being Delivered to Blue-Bubble Friends? Check Cellular Data

Here’s a tricky situation that threw one of our clients for a loop
recently. Texts they sent in Messages via iMessage (indicated by blue
bubbles) to their son, letting him know they were stopping by weren’t
being delivered, making their visits a surprise. But other texts worked
fine. The problem, it turned out, was that Cellular Data had somehow
gotten turned off in Settings  Cellular. So messages worked fine as
long as the iPhone was on Wi-Fi at home, but as soon as they were on the
road using a cellular connection, the iPhone could no longer communicate
with the Internet. In theory, Messages should fall back to SMS
(indicated by green bubbles), which doesn’t require cellular data, but
that doesn’t always happen. The fix? Just enable Settings  Cellular 
Cellular Data again.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SMS.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SMS.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/imessages-not-delivered/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/imessages-not-delivered/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>New M1 Pro and M1 Max Chips Power the 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Last year, Apple started to transition Macs away from Intel processors
to its custom M1 system-on-a-chip. The M1’s performance is stellar, but
Apple has used it only in low-end models so far: the MacBook Air,
13-inch MacBook Pro, Mac mini, and new 24-inch iMac. For professionals
looking for more power, Apple unveiled the future of high-end Macs at
its October 18th
Unleashed
event.

Two new chips—the M1 Pro and M1 Max—increase performance
significantly beyond the M1, and Apple built them into new 14-inch and
16-inch MacBook Pro models along with features that respond to
criticisms of previous models. Welcome as these new MacBook Pros are,
many people were also hoping to see an Apple silicon refresh of the
popular 27-inch iMac. That didn’t happen, but Apple released several
other music-related products and services at the event.

AirPods, HomePod mini, Apple Music, and Monterey Announcements

In a quick set of announcements at the start of its event, Apple
revealed an update to the popular AirPods, new colors of the HomePod
mini, and a budget pricing tier for Apple Music. Plus, press releases
revealed the ship date for macOS 12 Monterey.


  
    Third-generation AirPods: Building on the success of the classic
AirPods and AirPods Pro, Apple redesigned the third-generation
AirPods to
have shorter mic stalks, force sensor controls, support for spatial
audio, Adaptive EQ, longer battery life, wireless case charging, and
sweat and water resistance. They cost $179; the second-generation
AirPods remain available for $129.

  
  
    New HomePod mini colors: Looking to coordinate your electronics
with your decor? In November, the $99 HomePod
mini will be available
in blue, orange, and yellow, as well as the traditional black and
white.

  
  
    Apple Music Voice Plan: A new $4.99-per-month Apple Music
Voice Plan reduces the
cost of Apple Music for those who interact with the streaming
service largely through Siri, but it lacks lyrics, music videos,
spatial and lossless audio, and support for non-Apple devices.

  
  
    macOS 12 Monterey release date: Hidden in the fine print in
Apple’s press releases was the fact that macOS 12
Monterey—along with
iOS 15.1, iPadOS 15.1, watchOS 8.1, and tvOS 15.1—will become
available on October 25th. We strongly recommend that you do not
upgrade to Monterey until we give the go-ahead. If you’ve already
upgraded to the other new operating systems, it should be safe to
install those updates a week or two after release.
  


New 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros Answer Customer Desires

Apple’s professional MacBook
Pro has been a workhorse of
the Mac lineup for years, offering high-end performance in a portable
package. Since 2016, however, customers have expressed irritation at
Apple’s removal of ports other than Thunderbolt 3, the loss of MagSafe
magnetic charging, and the Touch Bar replacing traditional F-keys.
Here’s how the new MacBook Pros respond to those concerns.


  
    Ports: Previously, the MacBook Pro had just four Thunderbolt 3
ports, forcing users to carry dongles to connect to legacy devices.
The new models still lack USB-A ports but supplement three
Thunderbolt 4 ports with an HDMI port for video, an SDXC card slot
for camera media, and a headphone jack.

  
  
    MagSafe: Although you can charge using the Thunderbolt 4 ports,
most people will rely on the dedicated MagSafe 3 charging port. The
MacBook Pros (apart from the low-end 14-inch model) include powerful
chargers and a USB-C to MagSafe 3 charging cable capable of
fast-charging the devices. They should also provide longer battery
life than previous models.

  
  
    F-keys with Touch ID: The Touch Bar hasn’t been a success, never
migrating to any other Mac models and eliciting tepid support from
developers. With these new MacBook Pros, Apple has reversed course,
replacing the Touch Bar with traditional F-keys. A Touch ID sensor
remains available for authentication at the top-right corner of the
keyboard.
  


Although Apple did equip the 13-inch MacBook Pro with an M1 chip in
November 2020, it wasn’t notably faster than the cheaper but largely
comparable M1-based MacBook Air. We suspect no one will be complaining
about the performance of the new 14-inch and 16-inch models thanks to
the addition of Apple’s just-released M1 Pro and M1 Max chips.




  
    M1: For reference, last year’s M1 chip—widely acclaimed for
providing excellent performance—offers an 8-core CPU with four
performance and four efficiency cores, a 7-core or 8-core GPU, and
either 8 GB or 16 GB of unified memory.
  
  
    M1 Pro: The M1 Pro offers up to 1.7 times the performance of the
M1 thanks to a 10-core CPU that has eight performance and two
efficiency cores. Plus, its 16-core GPU is up to twice as fast as
the M1. The M1 Pro provides either 16 GB or 32 GB of unified memory,
and it increases the memory bandwidth by nearly three times, up to
200 gigabytes per second (GBps). To provide lower price points for
14-inch MacBook Pro configurations, Apple offers versions of the M1
Pro with an 8-core CPU (six performance and two efficiency cores) or
a 14-core GPU.
  
  
    M1 Max: The M1 Max has the same 10-core CPU as the M1 Pro but
provides a massive 32-core GPU with up to four times the performance
of the M1. The largest chip Apple has ever made, the M1 Max offers
either 32 GB or 64 GB of memory, and it doubles the M1 Pro’s memory
bandwidth to 400 GBps, nearly six times faster than the M1. A
lower-cost M1 Max configuration has a 24-core GPU.
  


Both the M1 Pro and M1 Max feature an Apple-designed media engine that
accelerates video processing while maximizing battery life. Both also
have dedicated acceleration for the ProRes professional video codec for
working with 4K and 8K video. The M1 Max doubles the M1 Pro’s
performance for video encoding and provides two ProRes accelerators. In
other words, if you’re working with video, these new Macs are going to
scream, particularly with an M1 Max.

Apple didn’t stop after radically improving performance and bringing
back beloved features. The new MacBook Pros feature new Liquid Retina
XDR displays based on technology used in the latest iPad Pro models.

Most notably, for those who need more screen space than the 13-inch
MacBook Pro can provide, the new MacBook Pro models have higher
resolution displays. The 14-inch screen has a 3024-by-1964 native
resolution that’s slightly larger than the previous 16-inch MacBook Pro
(3072‑by‑1920), and the new 16-inch model offers even more pixels with a
3456-by-2234 resolution. The new displays are more than twice as bright
as the previous models, and they support ProMotion, which adjusts the
screen refresh rate (and thus power consumption) to match the needs of
the onscreen content.

On the downside, Apple brought the new displays so close to the case
edges that the new 1080p FaceTime HD camera (better videoconferencing
quality but no Center Stage support) lives in an iPhone-like notch that
cuts the Mac menu bar in half. Full-screen apps can avoid the notch.
Although the notch isn’t ideal, iPhone users seldom notice it after a
short while, and we expect the same will be true here.



The only other negative for the new 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pro
models is weight. They’re both about 0.4 pounds (0.18 kg) heavier than
the models they replace, at 3.5 pounds (1.6 kg) for the 14-inch model
and 4.7 or 4.8 pounds (2.1 or 2.2 kg) for the 16-inch model—the M1 Max
configurations are a bit heavier.

Despite the notch and the weight, these are impressive new entries in
the Mac lineup, and we anticipate they’ll be well-received by users who
are happy to pay more for top-of-the-line machines. The 14-inch MacBook
Pro starts at $1999 and the 16-inch model at $2499. Numerous options
are available, so you can choose an M1 Pro or M1 Max for either size,
and pick from 16 GB, 32 GB, and 64 GB unified memory configurations.
When it comes to storage (which Apple says is also more than twice as
fast as previous SSDs), your choices are 512 GB, 1 TB, 2 TB, 4 TB, and 8
TB. Beware that the 8 TB SSD will cost you $2400.



We can’t make informed recommendations about what options you should
choose until users start testing their real-world workflows against the
M1 Pro and M1 Max and see how much memory is really necessary. For now,
let your budget be your guide, and aim for an M1 Max if you work with
video. You can place orders with Apple now, but be warned that global
supply chain issues may mean waiting for some configurations.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Unleashed.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Unleashed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/new-macbooks/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/new-macbooks/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Safari 15</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ New Features to Try (Or Not) in Safari 15

Along with a new version of Safari in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, Apple has
released Safari 15 for macOS 11 Big Sur and macOS 10.15 Catalina. Why do
this before macOS 12 Monterey ships? Some of the browser’s new
capabilities—notably the Tab Groups feature—integrate it more deeply
into your Apple device experience by syncing across devices. So,
assuming you have Safari 15 on at least some of your devices, what’s
new, and is it any good?

New Tab Bar Interface

For Safari 15, Apple tried to minimize the tab bar interface to occupy
less screen real estate and stand out less from the content of Web pages
by co-opting the color of each page. Early betas were met with a litany
of complaints from testers, and Apple pulled back in the eventual
releases, offering settings that let you retain the old interface. How
that plays out varies between the iPhone, iPad, and Mac:


  
    iPhone: Apple combined the address bar and tab bar into a single
set of controls at the bottom of the screen, where they’re easier to
reach with your thumb while working one-handed and where you can
swipe left and right to switch tabs. Plus, the status bar area at
the top of the screen takes on the color from the current site,
which isn’t necessarily a visual win. This is a huge change from the
controls appearing at the top, so if you don’t like it, go to
Settings  Safari and switch from Tab Bar (below left) to Single Tab
(below right). Turn off Allow Website Tinting (also below right) if
you don’t like the colorizing.

  
  
    iPad: Displays on the iPad are relatively small, so saving some
vertical space with the new Compact Tab Bar could be helpful.
However, since the tab bar automatically minimizes when you scroll
down a page, reducing its size when it’s visible isn’t as much of a
win as it might seem. And the colorized tab bar can be shockingly
bright. In Settings  Safari, you can choose between Compact Tab Bar
(below top) and Separate Tab Bar (below bottom); either way,
consider disabling Show Color in Tab Bar.

  
  
    Mac: Laptop screens aren’t huge, and Safari doesn’t minimize its
tab bar when you scroll, as it does on the iPhone and iPad, so
saving some vertical space might be welcome on a smaller screen. But
the way the Compact layout embeds the address field inside a tab and
reduces the number of buttons you can see may perturb you (below
top). Once again, the colorized tab bar can be glaring. To revert to
something closer to the old look, in Safari  Preferences  Tabs,
select Separate for the tab layout (below bottom), and disable Show
Color in Tab Bar to keep the controls gray regardless of the site
color.

  


Voice Search

For many searches, it’s easier to speak than type, and Apple has made
doing that even faster with Voice Search on the iPhone and iPad. Tap the
current tab to display the address field, tap the microphone button, and
speak instead of typing. As soon as you stop, Safari performs the
search. You can even navigate directly to a site by speaking its URL,
like “apple dot com.” Sadly, Apple didn’t extend this feature to the Mac
version of Safari 15.



Tab Switcher

In iOS 14 and earlier, Safari used a card stack metaphor for its tab
switcher (below left), which could make it hard to see what each tab
contained. In Safari in iOS 15, Apple took a cue from the iPad and Mac
versions of the app and moved to a grid interface for the tab switcher
(below right). You can drag the tab thumbnails around to organize them
and remove them by tapping an X button (weirdly located in the
upper-right corner) or swiping them left off-screen. You can also bring
up the option to close all open tabs by pressing and holding Done at the
lower right corner of the screen.



Tab Groups

If you struggle under the cognitive load of dozens of unrelated tabs,
the new Tab Groups feature might help. With it, you can collect tabs
into as many groups as you like and switch among them. You work with tab
groups in either the tab switcher interface (iPhone and iPad with the
Separate Tab Bar) or the sidebar (Mac and iPad with the Compact Tab
Bar).

To open the tab switcher on the iPhone, tap the tab button in the lower-right corner of the
screen; on the iPad, tap the different-looking tab button in the upper-right corner. Once
you have the tab switcher open, tap X Tabs to reveal the Tab Groups
menu. To show the sidebar on either the iPad or the Mac, tap or click
the sidebar button in the upper-left corner of the
tab bar.

Once you have the Tab Groups menu or sidebar showing:


  
    To create a new tab group on the iPhone’s or iPad’s Tab Groups menu,
tap New Empty Tab Group, name it, and tap Save. In the sidebar on a
Mac or iPad, use the New Tab Group button at the top (or choose File 
New Empty Tab Group on the Mac). You can also use New Tab Group from
X Tabs to create a tab group from currently open tabs.
  
  
    To switch to a different tab group, tap it in the Tab Groups menu on
an iPhone or iPad, or access it from the sidebar on a Mac or iPad.
  
  
    To delete a tab group, swipe left on it in the Tab Groups menu or
sidebar to reveal a delete icon on an iPhone or iPad; on the Mac,
Control-click it and choose Delete.
  




Shared with You

Ever gone spelunking through Messages to find a link someone sent you?
Safari 15’s new Shared with You feature should help. It automatically
collects all Web pages you receive in Messages into a new Shared with
You section of the Safari start page. On the iPad and Mac, there’s also
a Shared with You item in the sidebar.



Customizable Start Page

Speaking of the start page, if you want to customize which headings
appear and in what order, you can now do that on the iPhone and iPad.
(Choosing which headings appear has long been possible on the Mac by
clicking the little settings button in the lower-right corner, but
reordering isn’t possible there.)

Create a new tab to view the start page, scroll to the bottom, and tap
Edit. Then disable any headings you don’t want to see and drag the
remaining ones into your desired order. You can also choose among
several Apple-provided background images and have your start page
settings sync to your other devices.



Other Stuff

Two final new features may be welcome but probably won’t rock your
world:


  
    Pull to refresh: If you need to reload a Web page on the iPhone
or iPad, either you can tap the reload button in the address field
if it’s visible with your tab bar settings, or you can now just pull
down with your finger from the top of a page.
  
  
    HTTPS upgrade: If you visit a website that supports encrypted
HTTPS but is also loading insecure content over unencrypted HTTP,
Safari will now ensure that you connect to it over HTTPS so your
entire connection is secure.
  


There you have it! Check out the new features in Safari 15 and let them
improve your browsing experience.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariiOS.png</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-SafariiOS.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/safari/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/safari/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Forget Wi-Fi Networks</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ When It Comes to Wi-Fi Networks, Sometimes It’s Better to Forget

It’s easy, particularly when traveling, to end up connecting to a Wi-Fi
network that doesn’t provide Internet access, requires credentials you
don’t have, or lacks access to the network’s printer. Unfortunately,
once your iPhone, iPad, or Mac has connected to such a network, it may
reconnect to it later, causing consternation when things don’t work. The
solution? Whenever you realize a Wi-Fi network is worthless, forget it.
(The network, that is.) On the Mac, open System Preferences  Network  Wi-Fi  Advanced  Wi-Fi, select the network in the list (you don’t
have to be connected to it), click the – button, and click Remove. On
an iPhone or iPad, when you’re connected to the offending network, go to
Settings  Wi-Fi, tap the i button to the right of the current network,
and tap Forget This Network on the next screen.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSWiFi.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSWiFi.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/forget-wi-fi-networks/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/forget-wi-fi-networks/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>434: Interview With Jon Brown CEO of Grove Technologies</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Topics:


  
    We welcome Jon Brown of Grove Technologies. Jon is a long time VIP supporter of the show.
  
  
    Jon recalls attending a WWE even with the CCP crew, thanks to Joe’s sister.
  
  
    Starting a new business proved to be challenging initially. He talks about his learning curve and experiences building his current business.
  
  
    Jon has a concept like Uber for Tech Support.
  
  
    Grove Technologies is going to offer its internal SaaS based tool for other businesses and industries. There are integrations built for other tools like Addigy, Watchman, Jamf, etc.
  
  
    Working with others as a sub contractor can help broaden your area of expertise as a company.
  
  
    Hiring remote technicians has proven to be useful to Jon’s business model.
  
  
    Should you increase your onsite rate vs remote?
  
  
    Do your clients care if you or your staff make onsite visits to their offices?
  
  
    Grove Technologies has put their stake in the ground about being a remote only support company.
  
  
    People still don’t seem to grasp the concept of password management or Multi-Factor Authentication.
  
  
    Cybersecurity training for end users can be incredibly useful. It can also provide some discounts with insurance.
  
  
    Malwarebytes for Mac proves to be less powerful than the Windows version.
  
  
    Hook Security and Breach Secure Now are two big services to help with employee training.
  
  
    Jerry has some recommended security methods for his clients.
  
  
    Customers have a tendency to conflate security terms like VPN vs firewall.
  
  
    Jon wants you to become a sponsor of the show!
  











  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  

 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-CMDCTRLPWR.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-CMDCTRLPWR.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/command-control-power-10-13-21-interview-with-jon=brown-ceo-grove-technologies/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/command-control-power-10-13-21-interview-with-jon=brown-ceo-grove-technologies/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>iCloud Plus</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ What Is iCloud+ and What Can You Do With It?

As you upgrade to iOS 15, iPadOS 15 (and macOS 12 Monterey by the end of
the year), you’re going to see references to iCloud+. You might even
already be an iCloud+ subscriber! That’s because
iCloud+ is Apple’s
new name for what you get if you pay for additional iCloud storage for
yourself and up to five family members, which has been possible for a
long time.

iCloud+ comes with some new features as well, namely iCloud Private
Relay (still in beta), Hide My Email, and Custom Email Domain, along
with expanded HomeKit Secure Video support. Three tiers of iCloud+ match
up with the previous storage tiers:


  
    50 GB for $0.99 per month gets you all the iCloud+ features
plus HomeKit Secure Video support for one camera
  
  
    200 GB for $2.99 per month gets you all the iCloud+ features
plus HomeKit Secure Video support for five cameras
  
  
    2 TB for $9.99 per month gets you all the iCloud+ features plus
HomeKit Secure Video support for unlimited cameras
  


We expect that most people will subscribe to iCloud+ largely for the
extra storage—Apple provides only 5 GB of iCloud storage for
free—but once you’re paying for more storage, the other new features
are welcome. Let’s look at each.



iCloud Private Relay

Whenever you browse the Internet, your privacy can be compromised in two
ways. First, anyone on your local network can see the names of the
websites you access based on your DNS lookups. Second, the websites you
visit record the IP address of your computer, which makes it easier for
advertisers to track you across multiple sites.

iCloud Private Relay,
which Apple says will come out of beta by the end of the year, attempts
to block such tracking by encrypting your Safari traffic (plus DNS
queries and most non-HTTPS Web queries), sending it through two proxy
servers, and associating it with a geographically reasonable but
otherwise anonymous IP address. That way, the first proxy server (which
Apple runs) knows who you are but not what site you’re visiting. The
second proxy server (run by companies other than Apple) knows what site
you’re visiting, but not who you are.



Although Apple’s technique appeared to work well and early reports
suggest that it didn’t slow down traffic noticeably, networking is
notoriously complex. Apple wanted more time to ensure that iCloud
Private Relay works as promised with all network traffic, which is why
the feature remains in beta. However, nothing prevents you from trying
it out now. After you turn it on, you shouldn’t notice any difference
when using the Internet. Just make sure that if you have network-related
troubles, you remember to turn off iCloud Private Relay to remove it
from the troubleshooting equation.

To enable the feature, go to Settings  Your Name  iCloud 
Private Relay (Beta) and turn on the switch for Private Relay (Beta). In
the IP Address Location Settings screen, you can choose whether iCloud
Private Relay should try to maintain your general location or just make
sure it gets your country and time zone correct.



Hide My Email

Have you ever felt icky giving your email address to a questionable
website, knowing that it’s probably going to spam you with unwanted
solicitations? The new Hide My
Email service that’s
part of iCloud+ creates random, unique email addresses that
automatically forward to your inbox, either your Apple ID address or
another address associated with an email account configured on your
device. In fact, Apple has provided this option for some time with apps
that use the Sign in with Apple service—you can opt to give them a
random address instead of your real address.

To use Hide My Email, go to Settings  Your Name  iCloud  Hide My
Email. Make sure the Forward To address is the one you want, and then
tap Create New Address at the top. Either accept the address provided or
ask for a different one, give it a label and optional note so you know
where you used it, tap Next, and tap Done.



To stop receiving email from an address, tap it in the list and tap
Deactivate Email Address. In the Inactive Addresses list, you can see
such addresses and leave them for reference, reactivate them, or delete
them.



Custom Email Domain

Throughout the history of iCloud (including its predecessors iTools,
Mac.com, and MobileMe), users have received email addresses that end
with the mac.com, me.com, and icloud.com domains. If you wanted to
register your own custom email domain (like hoopyfroodemail.com, for
instance) and use that in a personalized email address, you had to rely
on another service like Gmail or Fastmail.

With iCloud+, it is at long last possible to connect up to five custom
domains and use them in
addition to the standard domains. You (and each person in your Family
Sharing group) can have up to three addresses for each domain. Note that
you must have a primary iCloud Mail email address set up and have
two-factor authentication enabled for your Apple ID.

Although the process for setting up a custom email domain isn’t that
difficult, it’s beyond the scope of this article. You need to have a
domain registered, update DNS records with your domain registrar,
associate email addresses with the custom domain, and verify your
settings. Apple provides
instructions,
and you should also read How to Set Up Custom Email Domains with
iCloud
Mail
from TidBITS for more real-world coverage. Reach out if you need help.

Our take is that this feature is welcome, but it’s just for hobbyists
and families. If you’re running a business of any sort, you should have
a custom email domain with a full-fledged email service. Contact us for
advice on the best solution for your particular situation—this is very
much not a “one size fits all” scenario.

HomeKit Secure Video

The final iCloud+ feature is HomeKit Secure Video, previously a free
bonus with the higher-level iCloud storage plans. It requires a
compatible third-party security camera and takes over from the
manufacturer’s app to ensure that no one can access your video,
including the camera maker and Apple. That’s a big deal—one of the
main problems with many third-party security cameras is that they
transmit and store video in insecure ways, making it possible for
evildoers to capture video from inside your house. (Yeah, it
happens.)

All that seems to have changed with iCloud+ is that Apple has added
HomeKit Secure Video to the 50 GB plan with support for one camera,
increased the number of supported cameras on the 200 GB plan to five,
and allowed an unlimited number of cameras for 2 TB plans.

As with custom email domains, the steps necessary to set up a security
camera in the Home app and work with HomeKit Secure Video are beyond the
scope of this article. Apple provides basic
instructions,
and the year-old article Apple’s HomeKit Secure Video Leverages iCloud
Storage and Preserves
Privacy
from TidBITS explains more and provides context.

Welcome as these features may be, they’re unlikely to compel upgrades
for those who don’t need more than the 5 GB of free iCloud storage.
However, it’s so common to need more iCloud space for photos, backups,
and files that we anticipate lots of people taking advantage of the
iCloud+ features that come along for the ride.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iCloudPlus.png</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iCloudPlus.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/icloud-plus/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/icloud-plus/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Update DND in Focus</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ After Upgrading to iOS 15, Check Do Not Disturb in Focus Settings

In iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, Apple expanded the concept of Do Not Disturb to
what it calls Focus. You can create a Focus for different types of
activities, so only specific people and apps can break through your cone
of silence at appropriate times. Focus subsumes the old Do Not Disturb
functionality, and your settings may not transfer when you upgrade,
leaving you open to being woken at night by a previously silenced
notification. To check and reset things to your liking, visit Settings  Focus  Do Not Disturb. If necessary, tap Add Schedule or Automation
to set a schedule or try the new Smart Activation option. Then decide
who, potentially beyond those in your Favorites, should be able to get
through, along with any apps that might be essential. Note that you
shouldn’t enable the Do Not Disturb switch at the top—that turns on
the Do Not Disturb Focus immediately.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-DND.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-DND.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/update-dnd-in-focus/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/update-dnd-in-focus/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Bulging batteries</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Beware the Bulging Battery! (And What to Do If Yours Expands)

We’ve been seeing a spate of bulging batteries of late, both in Mac
laptops and iPhones. A bulging battery is a Very Bad Thing™ and must be
dealt with immediately because it could catch fire or even explode. As
lithium-ion batteries age, the chemical reactions that produce power no
longer complete fully, resulting in the creation of gasses that can
cause the battery to swell. Additionally, manufacturing errors or damage
to the membranes that separate the internal layers of the battery can
also lead to swelling.

What to Look For

With Mac laptops, a variety of problems—some rather subtle—can
indicate that the internal battery is swelling, including the screen not
closing properly, a gap between the upper and lower parts of the case, a
failure to sit perfectly flat, problems clicking the trackpad, or
keyboard keys malfunctioning.



With an iPhone or iPad, a swollen battery is usually obvious because it
starts to warp the case and can even crack the screen—it all depends
on where the swelling takes place and what part of the device gives way
first.



What to Do

When you discover a bulging battery, unplug the device immediately and
turn it off as soon as you can. Continued charging or use could lead to
a fire or explosion. However, if the device is still functional and you
need to copy data off or let a final backup run, try to put it in a
place where it’s less likely to cause problems—on a concrete, stone,
or tile surface, for instance, and preferably outside as long as it’s
not wet, hot, or in the sun.

In some cases, as with older MacBooks, it’s relatively easy to
disassemble the case and remove the battery. If you feel comfortable
doing that, you may be able to reduce the chances of further damage.
It’s much harder to work on iPhones and iPads.

Make sure you’re somewhere well-ventilated and safe, with easy access to
outside and preferably a foam-based fire extinguisher at hand. If a fire
does start, water will also put it out—make sure to have plenty on
hand. Be sure to wear eye protection and gloves. Also, make sure you
have somewhere safe to store the battery once removed, such as a metal
can with a lid or with sand in it. Finally, be super careful around the
battery, and whatever you do, do not puncture the swollen cell—some of
the gases could be harmful.

Once you’ve removed the battery from the device, you must take it
somewhere for recycling. Under no circumstances should you send it via
the mail or put it in the regular garbage. Although various
companies—including Apple, Best Buy, Home Depot, and Lowes—recycle
batteries, call your local store first to see if they take swollen
batteries (they may not be equipped to do so safely). Better yet, check
with your county or municipality to see where you should take hazardous
waste.

For additional details and advice, see iFixit’s
guide
and the many comments.

Getting Your Device Fixed

The best-case scenario is that you have AppleCare+ on the device such
that Apple will fix it for you. However, that’s a bit unlikely because
batteries usually bulge only on older devices. Regardless of AppleCare
status, Apple offers battery service and
recycling,
and if you have an Apple
Store or
Apple Authorized Service Provider
nearby, that’s a good option. Independent repair shops can also likely
do this work; make sure they have plenty of experience with your device
and offer a warranty for their parts and labor.

Although it’s possible to replace batteries yourself—refer to the
iFixit site for instructions and links
to replacement batteries—it can be finicky work, particularly in
iPhones and iPads, and you may not save that much money in the end.

Sadly, particularly with an older iPhone, the damage from the bulging
battery may prevent a repair from being worthwhile. The iPhone X
pictured above still worked fine even though the swollen battery broke
its screen, but it wasn’t worth the money to replace the battery and the
screen for a 4-year-old iPhone. In such cases, recycle the entire unit
with the appropriate hazardous waste facility.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-MacbookBatteries.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-MacbookBatteries.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/bulging-batteries/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/bulging-batteries/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>About That Worrying Message Saying Your Password Has Been Breached?</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ In iOS 14, Apple added a feature that warns you when one of your website
passwords stored in iCloud Keychain has appeared in a data breach. We’ve
fielded some questions of late from people worrying if the message is
legitimate, and if so, what they should do. What has happened is that
online criminals have stolen username and password data from a company,
and your credentials were included in that data breach. You should
indeed change your password immediately, and it’s fine to let the iPhone
suggest a strong password for you. Or, if it makes you feel more
comfortable, you can usually change the password in Safari on your Mac
instead. Either way, make sure it’s unique—never reuse passwords
across multiple sites!


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSSecurity.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-iOSSecurity.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/about-that-worrying-message-saying-your-password-has-been-breached-/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/about-that-worrying-message-saying-your-password-has-been-breached-/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>The Plug Is Mightier Than the Puck - Wireless Charging Is Wildly Inefficient</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ In 2017, Apple added support for Qi wireless charging to the iPhone 8
and iPhone X, and with the iPhone 12 lineup, it introduced its own
MagSafe wireless charging technology. There’s no denying the convenience
of wireless charging, but keep in mind that it’s extremely inefficient
compared to wired charging. Individually, that may not matter much when
you’re charging overnight from a wall-connected charger. But across
billions of phones, it’s more problematic. One estimate suggests that
wireless charging requires nearly 50% more
power
than cable. And if you’re charging from a wireless battery pack, wasting
that juice means less of a top-up before exhausting the battery pack.
Charging speed suffers too. In short, to charge your iPhone quickly and
efficiently, whether from a wall-connected charger or a battery pack,
stick with the traditional Lightning cable.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Charging.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Charging.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/the-plug-is-mightier-than-the-puck-wireless-charging-is-wildly-inefficient/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/the-plug-is-mightier-than-the-puck-wireless-charging-is-wildly-inefficient/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Sort Your Lists Differently in Reminders in iOS 14 and Big Sur</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ For many years, Apple’s Reminders app let you sort your lists, but in
just one way that applied to all lists equally. That was a problem if
you had a to-do list that you wanted to sort by Due Date and a list of
foods in your freezer that you wanted to sort by Creation Date (to see
which were older) or Title (for a simple alphabetical sort). Happily, in
iOS 14 and macOS 11 Big Sur, Apple finally addressed this limitation,
letting you sort each list independently. Your choices even sync across
all your devices! So if you had given up on sorting, or given up on
Reminders entirely because of this limitation, on the Mac, check out the
View  Sort By menu, and in iOS and iPadOS, tap the ••• button and then
Sort By.


 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Stickies.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Stickies.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/sort-your-lists-differently-in-reminders-in-ios-14-and-big-sur/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/sort-your-lists-differently-in-reminders-in-ios-14-and-big-sur/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Losing the Occasional Important Message? Set up a Ham Filter</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ Although spam remains as much of a scourge as ever, spam filters have
improved enough that most people see relatively little spam and lose
relatively few legitimate messages (known as “ham”) to spam filters.
However, good email messages are still sometimes caught by spam filters.
To reduce the chance of missing an important message, consider making a
“ham filter.” A ham filter looks for certain words—usually proper
nouns—that are likely to appear only in legitimate messages and then
marks such messages as Not Spam or moves them out of a Spam folder.
(This capability is available in Gmail and can be emulated with multiple
rules that you create in Apple’s Mail preferences, and likely in other
systems as well; ask us about yours if you’re not sure.) Useful ham
words include the name of your city, local high school or college names,
club names or abbreviations, industry-specific terms, and any other
words that are specific to your community or profession. Always test a
possible ham word by first searching for it in your Spam folder to make
sure it appears only in legitimate messages.



 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Spam.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Spam.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/losing-the-occasional-important-message-set-up-a-ham-filter/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/losing-the-occasional-important-message-set-up-a-ham-filter/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>Apples 2021 Crop. Four iPhones, Two iPads and an Apple Watch</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ September is traditionally when new iPhones are ripe for the picking,
and this year’s crop is no exception. At its California
Streaming
event on September 14th, Apple unveiled four iPhone 13 models. Apple
also announced the expected Apple Watch Series 7, but entirely
unanticipated were an upgrade to the iPad and a redesigned iPad mini.

Left to the fine print in Apple’s press releases was the fact that iOS
15, iPadOS 16, and watchOS 8 will become available for download on
September 20th. As we’ve said before, you should wait at least a week or
two before installing them on essential devices, just in case some
unpleasant bug manifests itself. Regardless of when you upgrade, make a
backup right beforehand, just in case something goes wrong and you need
to erase and restore.

Let’s look at each of the new products.

iPhone 13 Models Evolve from Their iPhone 12 Equivalents

Some new iPhones are revolutionary, others are evolutionary. The iPhone
13, iPhone 13 mini, iPhone 13 Pro, and iPhone 13 Pro Max fall into the
latter category, improving on their iPhone 12 equivalents in numerous
ways while maintaining the same industrial design (albeit with a smaller
front notch) and core capabilities. There’s no shame in that, and these
are without a doubt the best iPhones Apple has ever made. So what’s new?



Most of Apple’s attention went into improving the cameras and photo- and
video-related functionality. The rear-facing dual-camera systems in the
iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 mini
have larger pixels and the sensor-shift optical image stabilization that
was previously available only in the iPhone 12 Pro Max, providing better
images in low-light photos and videos. The triple-camera systems in the
iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro
Max receive new sensors and
lenses that also improve low-light performance and enable 3x zoom (up
from 2x and 2.5x in the iPhone 12 equivalents). The new ultra-wide
camera in the Pro models also significantly improves macro photography,
capturing tiny subjects with a minimum focus distance of 2 centimeters.

All the iPhone 13 models offer three new and improved computational
photography features: Photographic Styles, Smart HDR 4, and Cinematic
mode. With Photographic Styles, the camera system automatically applies
your photographic preferences (a bit like custom filters) to photos in
real-time. Smart HDR 4 provides improved color, contrast, and lighting
for each subject in group photos.

Cinematic mode brings to iPhone videos a cinematic technique called
rack focus
that emphasizes people or objects in a shot by focusing on them while
blurring the rest of the scene. When enabled, Cinematic mode makes focus
changes automatically during shots, for example in response to a person
looking in a different direction or someone walking into the scene. You
can also manually change the focus during or after capture.



Beyond the cameras, Apple put effort into several other important iPhone
subsystems:


  
    A15 Bionic: Apple says the new A15 Bionic chip is the fastest
smartphone chip ever, though it never said how much faster it is
than last year’s A14 Bionic. Nevertheless, the A15 Bionic provides
stellar performance that enables the near-magical computational
photography features like Cinematic mode.
  
  
    Improved displays: The iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 mini have a
brighter Super Retina XDR display with a higher contrast ratio for
true blacks, all while being more power-efficient. The display in
the iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro Max is brighter yet and supports
Apple’s ProMotion technology that dynamically changes the screen
refresh rate as needed from 10 Hz to 120 Hz, either preserving
battery life or offering smooth video for games and movies.
  
  
    Longer battery life: Apple improved battery life with more
power-efficient components, larger batteries, and technologies like
ProMotion and Smart Data mode (which switches to LTE when 5G isn’t
needed). The iPhone 13 mini and iPhone 13 Pro offer 1.5 hours more
battery life than their predecessors, while the iPhone 13 and iPhone
13 Pro Max provide 2.5 hours more than theirs.
  
  
    5G in more countries: The iPhone 13 models support more 5G bands
for broader coverage and faster performance. Apple says that 5G
support on the iPhone 13 will include 200 carriers in 60 countries
and regions by the end of the year.
  


All four iPhone 13 models now start at 128 GB of storage, and the Pro
models offer a new 1 TB tier for those shooting a lot of video. Here are
the 128 GB prices; add $100 for 256 GB, $300 for 512 GB, and $500 for
1 TB:


  
    iPhone 13 mini: $699
  
  
    iPhone 13: $799
  
  
    iPhone 13 Pro: $999
  
  
    iPhone 13 Pro Max: $1099
  


You can pre-order starting at 5 AM Pacific on September 17th, with
delivery and in-store availability on September 24th. The iPhone 13 and
iPhone 13 mini come in five colors: pink, blue, midnight, starlight, and
(PRODUCT)RED. In contrast, the iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro Max come
in graphite, gold, silver, and sierra blue. The second-generation iPhone
SE ($399), iPhone 11 ($499), and iPhone 12 ($599) remain for sale as
well.

Generally speaking, we wouldn’t recommend upgrading from an iPhone 12
model unless you’re switching to the iPhone 13 mini to get a smaller
form factor or to one of the Pro models for the ultimate camera
capabilities. It’s easier to recommend an upgrade from an iPhone 11
model or earlier, given the easier-to-hold squared-off industrial design
and innovations like 5G and MagSafe that debuted with the iPhone 12 and
continue in the iPhone 13.

Apple Watch Series 7 Is Bigger, Brighter, and Incrementally Better

Much as with the iPhone 13, the new Apple Watch Series
7 doesn’t offer any
new sensors or surprising new features. Instead, it improves on last
year’s Series 6 in subtle yet welcome ways. Most notably, it boasts a
larger display with nearly 20% more screen area than the Series 6 and
over 50% more than the Series 3.



The larger screen can display about 50% more text than on the Series 6,
making it easier to read text messages or emails with less scrolling.
Apple also took advantage of the extra real-estate to add a full
keyboard in watchOS 8, enabling you to enter text by either tapping or
sliding your finger from letter to letter using Apple’s QuickPath
technology.



A couple of new watch faces take advantage of the larger display. The
dynamic Contour face animates throughout the day, pushing the dial to
the edge of the display and emphasizing the current hour. Plus, a new
Modular Duo face leverages the extra space to provide a pair of large,
data-rich complications.



A physical consequence of the larger display is that the Series 7 comes
in 41 mm and 45 mm sizes, replacing the 40 mm and 44 mm Series 6 models.
However, existing bands remain compatible. The front crystal has a
stronger and more robust geometry that’s over 50% thicker than on the
Series 6, making it more crack-resistant. It’s also now IP6X
dust-resistant for dirty environments, and it retains its WR50
water-resistance rating for swimming (but not scuba diving).

When your wrist is down, the Series 7’s always-on display is 70%
brighter indoors, making it easier to check the time discreetly. Despite
this, it continues to provide 18-hour battery life, and it charges 33%
faster than the Series 6, thanks to a new charging architecture and
Magnetic Fast Charger USB-C Cable. Charging for 45 minutes will get you
an 80% charge, and 8 minutes of juicing up before bed is enough for 8
hours of sleep tracking.

There are a few new fitness-related features, such as automatic
detection of Outdoor Cycle workouts and better fall detection algorithms
during workouts—including cycling—but most of them come with watchOS
8 and will work on older Apple Watch models as well.

Pricing for the Apple Watch Series 7 will start at $399, although it’s
easy to spend a lot more on different case materials, bands, and Hermès
models. The aluminum models will come in five colors: midnight,
starlight, green, a new blue, and (PRODUCT)RED; the stainless steel and
Apple Watch Edition models continue in existing colors. There will also
be new band colors. Apple hasn’t provided a date when you can order a
Series 7, saying only “later this fall.”

We can’t recommend an upgrade from the Apple Watch Series 6 or Series 5,
but if you’re limping along with an older watch whose battery is getting
weak, the Series 7 will be a compelling upgrade.

Upgraded iPad Gets Better Camera, True Tone, and More Storage

The base-model iPad has long been Apple’s best value, and with the
changes the company brought to the ninth-generation iPad, it’s even more
so. Apple improved the ninth-generation iPad in four ways:


  
    New front-facing FaceTime HD camera: This is the big one. Apple
replaced the anemic 1.2-megapixel front-facing FaceTime HD camera
with a 12-megapixel ultra-wide camera that supports the Center Stage
technology previously available only on the iPad Pro. Center Stage
zooms and pans to keep whoever is on camera centered and in focus.
And yes, the front-facing camera is now nominally better than the
8-megapixel rear-facing camera, which is a little weird.
  
  
    A13 Bionic chip: It’s not the latest and greatest, but the A13
Bionic is a generation newer than the previous iPad’s A12 Bionic,
and it should provide plenty of performance.
  
  
    True Tone display: Another feature swiped from the iPad Pro,
True Tone automatically adjusts the display’s color temperature
based on the ambient lighting conditions, making the screen easier
to read in different environments.
  
  
    Double the storage: Previously, the iPad started at 32 GB of
storage, which wasn’t enough to do much. Apple has now doubled the
base storage level to 64 GB and the next level to 256 GB.
  




Despite these improvements, the price for the basic iPad remains $329
($299 for education) in silver and space gray. It jumps to $479 for
256 GB of storage, and another $130 gives you 4G LTE connectivity at
either storage level. Overall, the ninth-generation iPad is a better
value than ever, and if you’re buying an iPad for anyone who doesn’t
need lots of power, it’s a no-brainer. It’s available now.

Redesigned iPad mini Mimics iPad Air

Even more surprising than the upgraded iPad was the redesigned
sixth-generation iPad mini. It resembles nothing so much as a smaller
iPad Air, with the same squared-off case design, an edge-to-edge
8.3-inch Liquid Retina display, Touch ID in the top button, and USB-C
charging and connectivity. It’s powered by the same new A15 Bionic chip
that’s in the iPhone 13 Pro.

Apple also significantly improved the iPad mini’s cameras, outfitting it
with a pair of 12-megapixel cameras. The rear-facing camera can now
shoot video in 4K resolution, and the front-facing camera supports
Center Stage. For ultimate portable connectivity, you can now get the
iPad mini with optional 5G wireless connectivity.



The main place where the sixth-generation iPad mini falls behind the
iPad Air is in accessories. It does support the second-generation Apple
Pencil, which sticks magnetically to the side, but it lacks the Smart
Connector that enables Apple’s well-regarded keyboards. You can still
use Bluetooth keyboards, but they don’t provide as integrated an
experience.

Storage options remain the same, but Apple dropped the price by $30,
making it $499 for a 64 GB configuration and $649 for 256 GB. Add
$150 to either configuration for 5G wireless connectivity. The iPad
mini comes in space gray, pink, purple, and starlight, and it’s
available now.

Realistically, you’re buying an iPad mini only if you value its
diminutive size over all else. It may not be worth upgrading from a
fifth-generation iPad mini unless it no longer meets your needs in some
way, but anyone who wants full iPad power in a small form factor will
appreciate the redesigned sixth-generation iPad mini.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Streaming.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-Streaming.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/apples-2021-crop-four-iphones-two-ipads-and-an-apple-watch/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/apples-2021-crop-four-iphones-two-ipads-and-an-apple-watch/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
         
        <item>
          <title>When Should You Upgrade to macOS 12 Monterey, iOS 15, iPadOS 15, watchOS 8, and tvOS 15?</title>
          <description><![CDATA[ September is here, which means that Apple will soon start releasing
major upgrades for all its operating systems. Apple previewed these
releases at its Worldwide Developers Conference in June, and many people
have been testing the public betas since. Once Apple judges macOS 12
Monterey, iOS 15, iPadOS 15, watchOS 8, and tvOS 15 to be ready for
prime time, the question arises—when should you install them?

(Note that we say when and not if. There’s no harm in delaying a
major operating system upgrade until Apple has sanded off rough edges
that slipped through testing. But waiting too long puts you at risk from
security vulnerabilities, increases compatibility annoyances, and
prevents you from taking advantage of new features. Plus, when you buy a
new Mac, iPhone, or iPad after these operating systems have shipped,
you’ll get the latest version, which could pose problems for your
existing apps. It’s best to be prepared if you have to replace a device
unexpectedly.)

In the past, we’ve offered separate takes on when you should install
each of Apple’s operating systems, but many of this year’s new features
are spread across multiple operating systems. For instance, the marquee
feature of this season’s releases is SharePlay, which promises to let
users watch videos, listen to audio, share screens, and more, all while
on a FaceTime call that could involve an iPhone, iPad, Mac, or Apple TV.
SharePlay sounds technically impressive—we’ll let you decide if it
interests you—but it’s not a reason to upgrade right away. Apple has
already announced that SharePlay is delayed and won’t ship until later
in the year.

So here’s the general upgrade order that we suggest, starting with the
iPad. Remember, always make a backup before upgrading a Mac, iPhone, or
iPad so you can revert right away if necessary.​

iPadOS 15

Upgrade your iPad to iPadOS
15 first. For the most
part, iPadOS is a superset of iOS, so why should you upgrade your iPad
before your iPhone? The big reason is that Apple has again taken a swing
at improving iPad multitasking, and the changes are worth investigating.
People who rely heavily on iPads will likely appreciate the new
multitasking features, and those for whom the iPad is less important
have nothing to lose by upgrading shortly after release.

Particularly welcome is a Multitasking menu at the top center of every
window that lets you create a full screen, Split View, Slide Over, and
in some cases (like Mail), a center window. There’s also a shelf at the
bottom of the screen that shows open windows within an app. You can
create Split View spaces by dragging one app from the App Switcher onto
another. Finally, a list of keyboard shortcuts appears when you press
and hold the Command key on an external keyboard. At long last,
discoverability comes to multitasking!



Apple migrated some iOS 14 improvements to iPadOS 15. Widgets can now
appear anywhere on the Home screen, and a new larger widget size lets
apps display more information. Also coming to iPadOS 15 is the App
Library, which automatically organizes all your apps into categories and
enables you to avoid cluttered Home screens.

If you’re a Notes user, you’ll appreciate the new Quick Note feature,
which lets you create a note with a swipe up from the corner of the
screen using your finger or an Apple Pencil. Quick Note can
automatically pull in highlighted text or links to a website or app, and
it’s easy to add more with the Apple Pencil or keyboard.

Other welcome changes include a Focus mode that reduces distractions;
voice searching and tab groups in Safari; FaceTime improvements; Live
Text that allows you to search for, select, copy, and translate text in
photos (on iPads with an A12 Bionic chip or later); and increased city
detail in Maps. ​

iOS 15

It’s usually safe to upgrade iOS fairly quickly because Apple puts
significant effort into ensuring that the new iOS version is a good
experience for those who buy the new iPhones that come with it. However,
because iPhones are so crucial to our everyday lives, it’s probably
worth delaying the upgrade to iOS
15 for a few weeks, just in
case. After that, you can install it and enjoy the new features.

Although SharePlay won’t arrive on day one, FaceTime still gets welcome
improvements inspired by competing videoconferencing systems. There’s
finally a grid view, Portrait mode for blurring the background,
different mic modes for focusing on your voice or on sound in the room,
the capability to include Windows and Android users, and FaceTime Web
links for scheduling and sharing calls.



Messages will collect links, images, and other content that your friends
have sent you in a new Shared with You section, which you’ll also find
in other Apple apps like Photos, Safari, Apple News, Music, and
Podcasts. Plus, when someone sends you multiple photos in Messages, they
appear as either a collage or a stack that you can swipe through. There
are also new Memoji options to try if you’re into that.

Other new features are similar to those in iPadOS 15, including Focus
mode, voice searches and tab groups in Safari, Live Text in Camera and
Photos, and improved city detail in Maps, which also gains immersive
walking instructions. ​

watchOS 8

Once you upgrade your iPhone to iOS 15, go ahead and upgrade your Apple
Watch to watchOS 8
right away. You may not even notice the difference since none of the
changes will force changes in your existing usage patterns.

New features include Portrait mode photos on your watch face, Memories
from Photos pushed to your watch, the capability to share photos via
Messages and Mail, integration with HomeKit security cameras, more
control over scenes and devices in the Home app, digital keys for
HomeKit locks, a new Mindfulness app that replaces the Breathe app, a
Pilates option in the Workout app, tracking of your sleeping respiratory
rate, and a Find Devices app for locating lost devices from your wrist.



tvOS 15

Why put tvOS ahead of macOS? The decision to upgrade to tvOS
15
is easy for most people. It’s unlikely to cause problems for your Apple
TV, and the new features won’t get in the way of basic TV watching.
Plus, if you have automatic updates turned on in Settings  Software
Updates, it will install automatically at some point after release.

You might not want to wait for the automatic update, though. There are
plenty of small but welcome improvements, such as the capability to sign
in to Apple TV apps using Face ID or Touch ID on your iPhone. The
playback interface has a redesigned scrubber that displays more
information. The Apple TV will automatically detect nearby AirPods and
show a notification to connect them, saving you a manual step. If you
have AirPods Pro or AirPods Max, you can listen to Apple TV audio with
dynamic head tracking. The TV app will include a “For All of You” row
based on the interests of everyone in the house (via Family Sharing).
Finally, you can ask a HomePod to play a particular show on the Apple TV
and even use one or two HomePod mini speakers as the default audio
output.



macOS 12 Monterey

The hardest upgrade decision revolves around your Mac, as always. For
the most part, macOS 11 Big Sur has been relatively solid, with fewer
complaints than plagued macOS 10.15 Catalina. Some beta testers believe
that macOS 12 Monterey is more of a refinement upgrade without the major
architectural changes that marked Big Sur and Catalina. That would
suggest more stability and the possibility of an easier and earlier
upgrade.

Plus, Monterey has some unique features. Most notable is Universal
Control, which lets you work seamlessly between multiple Macs and your
iPad, connected wirelessly or via USB. You can move the pointer from a
Mac to the iPad, type into iPad apps with your Mac’s keyboard, and even
drag and drop content from one Mac to another. Another welcome addition
is the option to use AirPlay to display video, play audio, or present
content from another Apple device to a Mac, something that has
previously been possible only in the other direction. Finally, Monterey
brings the Shortcuts automation app to the Mac, making it easier to
automate repetitive tasks without learning AppleScript or using the
aging Automator.



Apart from those features, you’ve already read about most of the
changes. They include FaceTime improvements, support for Focus mode,
Shared with You collections in Apple apps, tab groups (but not voice
searching, sadly) in Safari, a Quick Note hot corner activation option,
Live Text, and Maps enhancements.

You may find some of these features compelling, but we recommend waiting
to upgrade to Monterey for at least a few months. App compatibility
isn’t usually a big problem with the other operating systems, but most
of us rely on specific Mac apps—sometimes older versions—to get our
work done. Even once you’re confident your apps will work properly in
Monterey, there may be workflow or intra-office compatibility concerns
if some people upgrade and others don’t. And, of course, unanticipated
bugs could crop up at professionally inconvenient times—important work
takes place on Macs! So please, do not upgrade to Monterey without
checking with us first. With luck, the start of the new year will have
brought both the bug fixes and app updates necessary to give the green
light.
 ]]></description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          <link>https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-UpgradeWhen.jpg</link>
          <enclosure url="https://grovetech.co/assets/img/2021/Header-UpgradeWhen.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
          <permalink>https://grovetech.co/blog/when-should-you-upgrade-to-macos-12-monterey-ios-15-ipados-15-watchos-8-and-tvos-15-/</permalink>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://grovetech.co/blog/when-should-you-upgrade-to-macos-12-monterey-ios-15-ipados-15-watchos-8-and-tvos-15-/</guid>
        </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>